<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<bibliography>
   <PT>J</PT>
   <AU>Bedau, D; Liu, H; Sun, JZ; Katine, JA; Fullerton, EE; Mangin, S; Kent, AD</AU>
   <BA></BA>
   <BE></BE>
   <GP></GP>
   <AF>Bedau, D.; Liu, H.; Sun, J. Z.; Katine, J. A.; Fullerton, E. E.; Mangin, S.; Kent, A. D.</AF>
   <BF></BF>
   <CA></CA>
   <TI>Spin-transfer pulse switching: From the dynamic to the thermally activated regime</TI>
   <SO>APPLIED PHYSICS LETTERS</SO>
   <SE></SE>
   <BS></BS>
   <LA>English</LA>
   <DT>Article</DT>
   <CT></CT>
   <CY></CY>
   <CL></CL>
   <SP></SP>
   <HO></HO>
   <DE></DE>
   <ID>MAGNETIZATION REVERSAL; EXCITATIONS; NANOPILLARS; PARTICLE</ID>
   <AB>The effect of thermal fluctuations on spin-transfer switching has been studied for a broad range of time scales (subnanoseconds to seconds) in a model system, a uniaxial thin film nanomagnet. The nanomagnet is incorporated into a spin-valve nanopillar, which is subject to spin-polarized current pulses of variable amplitude and duration. Two physical regimes are clearly distinguished: a long pulse duration regime, in which reversal occurs by spin-transfer assisted thermal activation over an energy barrier, and a short-time large pulse amplitude regime, in which the switching probability is determined by the spin-angular momentum in the current pulse. (C) 2010 American Institute of Physics. [doi:10.1063/1.3532960]</AB>
   <C1>[Bedau, D.; Liu, H.; Kent, A. D.] NYU, Dept Phys, New York, NY 10003 USA; [Sun, J. Z.] IBM Corp, Thomas J Watson Res Ctr, Yorktown Hts, NY 10598 USA; [Katine, J. A.] Hitachi GST, San Jose Res Ctr, San Jose, CA 95135 USA; [Fullerton, E. E.] Univ Calif San Diego, CMRR, La Jolla, CA 92093 USA; [Mangin, S.] Nancy Univ, IJL, CNRS, UMR 7198, F-54042 Vandoeuvre Les Nancy, France</C1>
   <RP>Bedau, D (reprint author), NYU, Dept Phys, 4 Washington Pl, New York, NY 10003 USA.</RP>
   <EM>andy.kent@nyu.edu</EM>
   <RI>Fullerton, Eric/H-8445-2013; Sun, Jonathan/C-2773-2009</RI>
   <OI>Fullerton, Eric/0000-0002-4725-9509; </OI>
   <FU>USARO [W911NF0710643]; NSF-DMR [0706322, 1006575, 1008654]</FU>
   <FX>The research at NYU was supported by USARO Grant No. W911NF0710643 and NSF-DMR Grant Nos. 0706322 and 1006575. Research at UCSD was supported by NSF-DMR Grant No. 1008654</FX>
   <CR></CR>
   <NR>18</NR>
   <TC>45</TC>
   <Z9>45</Z9>
   <PU>AMER INST PHYSICS</PU>
   <PI>MELVILLE</PI>
   <PA>CIRCULATION & FULFILLMENT DIV, 2 HUNTINGTON QUADRANGLE, STE 1 N O 1, MELVILLE, NY 11747-4501 USA</PA>
   <SN>0003-6951</SN>
   <EI></EI>
   <BN></BN>
   <J9>APPL PHYS LETT</J9>
   <JI>Appl. Phys. Lett.</JI>
   <PD>DEC 27</PD>
   <PY>2010</PY>
   <VL>97</VL>
   <IS>26</IS>
   <PN></PN>
   <SU></SU>
   <SI></SI>
   <MA></MA>
   <BP></BP>
   <EP></EP>
   <AR>262502</AR>
   <DI>10.1063/1.3532960</DI>
   <D2></D2>
   <PG>3</PG>
   <WC>Physics, Applied</WC>
   <SC>Physics</SC>
   <GA>700TV</GA>
   <UT>WOS:000285768100047</UT>
   <PM></PM>
</bibliography>
