<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<bibliography>
   <PT>S</PT>
   <AU>Lindner, J; Burgler, DE; Mangin, S</AU>
   <BA></BA>
   <BE>Zabel, H; Farle, M</BE>
   <GP></GP>
   <AF>Lindner, Juergen; Buergler, Daniel E.; Mangin, Stephane</AF>
   <BF></BF>
   <CA></CA>
   <TI>The Influence of Magnetic Anisotropy on Current-Induced Spindynamics</TI>
   <SO>MAGNETIC NANOSTRUCTURES: SPIN DYNAMICS AND SPIN TRANSPORT</SO>
   <SE>Springer Tracts in Modern Physics</SE>
   <BS></BS>
   <LA>English</LA>
   <DT>Article; Book Chapter</DT>
   <CT></CT>
   <CY></CY>
   <CL></CL>
   <SP></SP>
   <HO></HO>
   <DE></DE>
   <ID>SPIN-POLARIZED CURRENT; TRANSFER TORQUE; MICROWAVE GENERATION; PERPENDICULAR ANISOTROPY; TUNNEL-JUNCTIONS; DOMAIN-WALLS; DRIVEN; MULTILAYERS; DYNAMICS; REVERSAL</ID>
   <AB>The chapter provides a short and intuitive introduction to the basic concept of spin-transfer torque and the field of spin-torque driven magnetization dynamics in nanopillar systems. The influence of spin-polarized currents on magnetic nano-objects may lead to current-induced magnetization reversal as well as current-driven magnetization dynamics. The quantities that determine the critical currents for magnetization switching and the influence of the relative orientation of magnetization and current polarization are discussed. We focus on the nanopillar geometry and address the influence of magnetic anisatropy on the spin-torque driven spindynamics. Selected experimental examples are given to illustrate the interplay between magnetic anisotropy and spin-transfer torque.</AB>
   <C1>[Lindner, Juergen] Univ Duisburg Essen, Fac Phys, D-47057 Duisburg, Germany; [Lindner, Juergen] Univ Duisburg Essen, Ctr Nanointegrat CeNIDE, D-47057 Duisburg, Germany; [Buergler, Daniel E.] Forschungszentrum Julich, Peter Grunberg Inst, Elect Properties PGI 6, D-52425 Julich, Germany; [Buergler, Daniel E.] Forschungszentrum Julich, Julich Aachen Res Alliance, Fundamentals Future Informat Technol JARA FIT, D-52425 Julich, Germany; [Mangin, Stephane] Nancy Univ, CNRS, Inst Jean Lamour Blvd Aiguillettes, F-54506 Vandoeuvre Les Nancy, France</C1>
   <RP>Lindner, J (reprint author), Univ Duisburg Essen, Fac Phys, Lotharstr 1, D-47057 Duisburg, Germany.</RP>
   <EM>juergen.lindner@uni-due.de; d.buergler@fz-juelich.de; stephane.mangin@ijl.nancy-universite.fr</EM>
   <RI>Buergler, Daniel/I-7408-2012</RI>
   <OI>Buergler, Daniel/0000-0002-5579-4886</OI>
   <FU></FU>
   <FX></FX>
   <CR></CR>
   <NR>89</NR>
   <TC>0</TC>
   <Z9>0</Z9>
   <PU>SPRINGER-VERLAG BERLIN</PU>
   <PI>BERLIN</PI>
   <PA>HEIDELBERGER PLATZ 3, D-14197 BERLIN, GERMANY</PA>
   <SN>0081-3869</SN>
   <EI></EI>
   <BN>978-3-642-32041-5</BN>
   <J9>SPRINGER TRAC MOD PH</J9>
   <JI></JI>
   <PD></PD>
   <PY>2013</PY>
   <VL>246</VL>
   <IS></IS>
   <PN></PN>
   <SU></SU>
   <SI></SI>
   <MA></MA>
   <BP>1</BP>
   <EP>35</EP>
   <AR></AR>
   <DI>10.1007/978-3-642-32042-2_1</DI>
   <D2>10.1007/978-3-642-32042-2</D2>
   <PG>35</PG>
   <WC>Nanoscience & Nanotechnology; Physics, Multidisciplinary</WC>
   <SC>Science & Technology - Other Topics; Physics</SC>
   <GA>BEV77</GA>
   <UT>WOS:000318317800002</UT>
   <PM></PM>
</bibliography>
