<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<bibliography>
   <PT>J</PT>
   <AU>Shi, Z; Du, J; Chantrell, RW; Mangin, S; Zhou, SM</AU>
   <BA></BA>
   <BE></BE>
   <GP></GP>
   <AF>Shi, Z.; Du, J.; Chantrell, R. W.; Mangin, S.; Zhou, S. M.</AF>
   <BF></BF>
   <CA></CA>
   <TI>Torque approach for tuning exchange bias training effect in polycrystalline NiFe/FeMn bilayers</TI>
   <SO>APPLIED PHYSICS LETTERS</SO>
   <SE></SE>
   <BS></BS>
   <LA>English</LA>
   <DT>Article</DT>
   <CT></CT>
   <CY></CY>
   <CL></CL>
   <SP></SP>
   <HO></HO>
   <DE></DE>
   <ID>ANISOTROPY</ID>
   <AB>In order to tune the exchange bias training effect, a torque approach is proposed. Torque loops are performed between two consecutive hysteresis loops by clockwise and counterclockwise rotation of the sample within an angular range under an in-plane external magnetic field. For the angular range from 0 degrees to 180 degrees the coercivity H(C) and the exchange field H(E) are both reduced and the pinning direction (PD) orientation is changed, exhibiting the first type training effect. For the angular range from -20 degrees to 380 degrees, H(C) and the PD orientation are almost unchanged although H(E) is reduced, exhibiting the second type training effect. (C) 2011 American Institute of Physics. [doi:10.1063/1.3569140]</AB>
   <C1>[Shi, Z.; Zhou, S. M.] Tongji Univ, Dept Phys, Shanghai 200092, Peoples R China; [Du, J.] Nanjing Univ, Natl Lab Solid State Microstruct, Nanjing 210093, Peoples R China; [Chantrell, R. W.] Univ York, Dept Phys, York YO10 5DD, N Yorkshire, England; [Mangin, S.] Nancy Univ, Inst Jean Lamour, F-54506 Vandoeuvre Les Nancy, France</C1>
   <RP>Shi, Z (reprint author), Tongji Univ, Dept Phys, Shanghai 200092, Peoples R China.</RP>
   <EM>shiming@tongji.edu.cn</EM>
   <RI>Shi, Zhong/B-5736-2012</RI>
   <OI>Shi, Zhong/0000-0002-6793-0304</OI>
   <FU>National Natural Science Foundation of China [50871030, 11074112, 10974032]; National Basic Research Program of China [2009CB929201]</FU>
   <FX>This work was supported by the National Natural Science Foundation of China under Grant Nos. 50871030, 11074112, and 10974032 and the National Basic Research Program of China under Grant No. 2009CB929201.</FX>
   <CR></CR>
   <NR>22</NR>
   <TC>10</TC>
   <Z9>10</Z9>
   <PU>AMER INST PHYSICS</PU>
   <PI>MELVILLE</PI>
   <PA>CIRCULATION & FULFILLMENT DIV, 2 HUNTINGTON QUADRANGLE, STE 1 N O 1, MELVILLE, NY 11747-4501 USA</PA>
   <SN>0003-6951</SN>
   <EI></EI>
   <BN></BN>
   <J9>APPL PHYS LETT</J9>
   <JI>Appl. Phys. Lett.</JI>
   <PD>MAR 21</PD>
   <PY>2011</PY>
   <VL>98</VL>
   <IS>12</IS>
   <PN></PN>
   <SU></SU>
   <SI></SI>
   <MA></MA>
   <BP></BP>
   <EP></EP>
   <AR>122507</AR>
   <DI>10.1063/1.3569140</DI>
   <D2></D2>
   <PG>3</PG>
   <WC>Physics, Applied</WC>
   <SC>Physics</SC>
   <GA>740PZ</GA>
   <UT>WOS:000288808200055</UT>
   <PM></PM>
</bibliography>
