<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<bibliography>
   <PT>J</PT>
   <AU>Tudosa, I; Katine, JA; Mangin, S; Fullerton, EE</AU>
   <BA></BA>
   <BE></BE>
   <GP></GP>
   <AF>Tudosa, Ioan; Katine, J. A.; Mangin, S.; Fullerton, Eric E.</AF>
   <BF></BF>
   <CA></CA>
   <TI>Perpendicular spin-torque switching with a synthetic antiferromagnetic reference layer</TI>
   <SO>APPLIED PHYSICS LETTERS</SO>
   <SE></SE>
   <BS></BS>
   <LA>English</LA>
   <DT>Article</DT>
   <CT></CT>
   <CY></CY>
   <CL></CL>
   <SP></SP>
   <HO></HO>
   <DE>antiferromagnetic materials; cobalt; magnetic multilayers; magnetic switching; magnetic transitions; magnetoelectronics; nanoelectronics; nanomagnetics; nanostructured materials; nickel; palladium; perpendicular magnetic anisotropy; spin fluctuations; spin polarised transport; spin valves</DE>
   <ID>MAGNETIZATION REVERSAL; MRAM</ID>
   <AB>Spin-torque switching of perpendicular anisotropy nanopillar spin valve devices with synthetic antiferromagnetic reference layers is presented. The use of composite reference layer reduces the dipolar interaction with the free layer yielding two remanent states. We derive a complete current-field phase diagram including minor loops of the free layer where we determine the relative dipolar fields and effective spin polarization of the reference layer in both the parallel and antiparallel configurations. We find the magnetic response of the reference layer relatively insensitive to the spin polarized current which may prove advantageous for spin-torque applications. (C) 2010 American Institute of Physics. [doi:10.1063/1.3441402]</AB>
   <C1>[Tudosa, Ioan; Fullerton, Eric E.] Univ Calif San Diego, Ctr Magnet Recording Res, La Jolla, CA 92093 USA; [Katine, J. A.] Hitachi Global Storage Technol, San Jose Res Ctr, San Jose, CA 95135 USA; [Mangin, S.] Nancy Univ, CNRS, Inst Jean Lamour, UMR 7198, F-54506 Vandoeuvre Les Nancy, France</C1>
   <RP>Tudosa, I (reprint author), Avalanche Technol, 48371 Fremont Blvd,Ste 101, Fremont, CA 94538 USA.</RP>
   <EM>efullerton@ucsd.edu</EM>
   <RI>Gastelois, Pedro/F-3891-2012; Fullerton, Eric/H-8445-2013</RI>
   <OI>Fullerton, Eric/0000-0002-4725-9509</OI>
   <FU></FU>
   <FX></FX>
   <CR></CR>
   <NR>17</NR>
   <TC>16</TC>
   <Z9>16</Z9>
   <PU>AMER INST PHYSICS</PU>
   <PI>MELVILLE</PI>
   <PA>CIRCULATION & FULFILLMENT DIV, 2 HUNTINGTON QUADRANGLE, STE 1 N O 1, MELVILLE, NY 11747-4501 USA</PA>
   <SN>0003-6951</SN>
   <EI></EI>
   <BN></BN>
   <J9>APPL PHYS LETT</J9>
   <JI>Appl. Phys. Lett.</JI>
   <PD>MAY 24</PD>
   <PY>2010</PY>
   <VL>96</VL>
   <IS>21</IS>
   <PN></PN>
   <SU></SU>
   <SI></SI>
   <MA></MA>
   <BP></BP>
   <EP></EP>
   <AR>212504</AR>
   <DI>10.1063/1.3441402</DI>
   <D2></D2>
   <PG>3</PG>
   <WC>Physics, Applied</WC>
   <SC>Physics</SC>
   <GA>603BP</GA>
   <UT>WOS:000278183200045</UT>
   <PM></PM>
</bibliography>
