<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<bibliography>
   <PT>J</PT>
   <AU>Cucchiara, J; Fullerton, EE; Kent, AD; Sun, JZ; Henry, Y; Mangin, S</AU>
   <BA></BA>
   <BE></BE>
   <GP></GP>
   <AF>Cucchiara, J.; Fullerton, Eric E.; Kent, A. D.; Sun, J. Z.; Henry, Y.; Mangin, S.</AF>
   <BF></BF>
   <CA></CA>
   <TI>Current-induced magnetization reversal in terms of power dissipation</TI>
   <SO>PHYSICAL REVIEW B</SO>
   <SE></SE>
   <BS></BS>
   <LA>English</LA>
   <DT>Article</DT>
   <CT></CT>
   <CY></CY>
   <CL></CL>
   <SP></SP>
   <HO></HO>
   <DE></DE>
   <ID></ID>
   <AB>Magnetization excitation and reversal induced by spin-transfer torques is described in terms of power received or dissipated in a macrospin system. This approach provides a clear and intuitive understanding of the effect of both applied magnetic fields and injected spin-polarized currents on magnetization reversal. It is illustrated by solving the case of magnetization reversal in a nanopillar spin valve with perpendicular magnetizations although the approach can be applied more generally. The appearance of critical currents below which spin-transfer torque is no longer efficient is explained by a break in the uniaxial symmetry of such structures.</AB>
   <C1>[Cucchiara, J.; Mangin, S.] Nancy Univ, CNRS, Inst Jean Lamour, Upv Metz, Vandoeuvre Les, France; [Fullerton, Eric E.] Univ Calif San Diego, Ctr Magnet Recording Res, San Diego, CA 92093 USA; [Kent, A. D.] NYU, Dept Phys, New York, NY 10003 USA; [Sun, J. Z.] IBM TJ Watson Res Ctr, Yorktown Hts, NY 10598 USA; [Henry, Y.] UDS, CNRS, Inst Phys & Chim Mat Strasbourg, Strasbourg, France</C1>
   <RP>Cucchiara, J (reprint author), Nancy Univ, CNRS, Inst Jean Lamour, Upv Metz, Vandoeuvre Les, France.</RP>
   <EM>stephane.mangin@ijl.nancy-universite.fr</EM>
   <RI>Fullerton, Eric/H-8445-2013; Sun, Jonathan/C-2773-2009</RI>
   <OI>Fullerton, Eric/0000-0002-4725-9509; </OI>
   <FU>French National Research Agency (ANR); NSF</FU>
   <FX>This work was supported in parts by the Friends contract of the French National Research Agency (ANR) and by the NSF.</FX>
   <CR></CR>
   <NR>15</NR>
   <TC>5</TC>
   <Z9>5</Z9>
   <PU>AMER PHYSICAL SOC</PU>
   <PI>COLLEGE PK</PI>
   <PA>ONE PHYSICS ELLIPSE, COLLEGE PK, MD 20740-3844 USA</PA>
   <SN>1098-0121</SN>
   <EI></EI>
   <BN></BN>
   <J9>PHYS REV B</J9>
   <JI>Phys. Rev. B</JI>
   <PD>SEP 21</PD>
   <PY>2011</PY>
   <VL>84</VL>
   <IS>10</IS>
   <PN></PN>
   <SU></SU>
   <SI></SI>
   <MA></MA>
   <BP></BP>
   <EP></EP>
   <AR>100405</AR>
   <DI>10.1103/PhysRevB.84.100405</DI>
   <D2></D2>
   <PG>4</PG>
   <WC>Physics, Condensed Matter</WC>
   <SC>Physics</SC>
   <GA>822XL</GA>
   <UT>WOS:000295083800001</UT>
   <PM></PM>
</bibliography>
