<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<bibliography>
   <PT>J</PT>
   <AU>Schmitt, O; Steil, D; Alebrand, S; Ganss, F; Hehn, M; Mangin, S; Albrecht, M; Mathias, S; Cinchetti, M; Aeschlimann, M</AU>
   <BA></BA>
   <BE></BE>
   <GP></GP>
   <AF>Schmitt, Oliver; Steil, Daniel; Alebrand, Sabine; Ganss, Fabian; Hehn, Michel; Mangin, Stephane; Albrecht, Manfred; Mathias, Stefan; Cinchetti, Mirko; Aeschlimann, Martin</AF>
   <BF></BF>
   <CA></CA>
   <TI>Kerr and Faraday microscope for space- and time-resolved studies</TI>
   <SO>EUROPEAN PHYSICAL JOURNAL B</SO>
   <SE></SE>
   <BS></BS>
   <LA>English</LA>
   <DT>Article</DT>
   <CT></CT>
   <CY></CY>
   <CL></CL>
   <SP></SP>
   <HO></HO>
   <DE></DE>
   <ID>ANGULAR-MOMENTUM; ULTRAFAST; DEMAGNETIZATION; REVERSAL</ID>
   <AB>We present a multi-purpose scanning magneto-optical microscope for the investigation of magnetic thin films. The setup can be used for both static and time-resolved (pump-probe) measurements. It is moreover compatible with samples with arbitrary magnetic anisotropy, as it allows Kerr measurements in polar and longitudinal geometry as well as in transmission (Faraday geometry). We demonstrate that the microscope can be used in the following modi: (i) static imaging mode (in polar Kerr and Faraday geometry) with a spatial resolution of 1.7 mu m; (ii) time-resolved mode (polar Kerr geometry) with a temporal resolution of 300 femtoseconds.</AB>
   <C1>[Schmitt, Oliver; Steil, Daniel; Alebrand, Sabine; Mathias, Stefan; Cinchetti, Mirko; Aeschlimann, Martin] Univ Kaiserslautern, Dept Phys, D-67663 Kaiserslautern, Germany; [Schmitt, Oliver; Steil, Daniel; Alebrand, Sabine; Mathias, Stefan; Cinchetti, Mirko; Aeschlimann, Martin] Univ Kaiserslautern, Res Ctr OPTIMAS, D-67663 Kaiserslautern, Germany; [Ganss, Fabian; Albrecht, Manfred] Tech Univ Chemnitz, Inst Phys, D-09107 Chemnitz, Germany; [Hehn, Michel; Mangin, Stephane] Nancy Univ, CNRS, Dept Phys Mat & Mat P2M, Inst Jean Lamour,UMR 7198, Upv Metz, France</C1>
   <RP>Schmitt, O (reprint author), Univ Kaiserslautern, Dept Phys, Erwin Schroedinger Str 46, D-67663 Kaiserslautern, Germany.</RP>
   <EM>oschmitt@rhrk.uni-kl.de</EM>
   <RI>Cinchetti, Mirko/F-9769-2010</RI>
   <OI>Cinchetti, Mirko/0000-0003-0735-8921</OI>
   <FU></FU>
   <FX></FX>
   <CR></CR>
   <NR>20</NR>
   <TC>0</TC>
   <Z9>0</Z9>
   <PU>SPRINGER</PU>
   <PI>NEW YORK</PI>
   <PA>233 SPRING ST, NEW YORK, NY 10013 USA</PA>
   <SN>1434-6028</SN>
   <EI>1434-6036</EI>
   <BN></BN>
   <J9>EUR PHYS J B</J9>
   <JI>Eur. Phys. J. B</JI>
   <PD>SEP 23</PD>
   <PY>2014</PY>
   <VL>87</VL>
   <IS>9</IS>
   <PN></PN>
   <SU></SU>
   <SI></SI>
   <MA></MA>
   <BP></BP>
   <EP></EP>
   <AR>219</AR>
   <DI>10.1140/epjb/e2014-50257-3</DI>
   <D2></D2>
   <PG>6</PG>
   <WC>Physics, Condensed Matter</WC>
   <SC>Physics</SC>
   <GA>AQ0EQ</GA>
   <UT>WOS:000342456000002</UT>
   <PM></PM>
</bibliography>
