<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<bibliography>
   <PT>J</PT>
   <AU>Da Silva, M; Dumesnil, K; Dufour, C; Hehn, M; Pierre, D; Lacour, D; Montaigne, F; Lengaigne, G; Robert, S</AU>
   <BA></BA>
   <BE></BE>
   <GP></GP>
   <AF>Da Silva, M.; Dumesnil, K.; Dufour, C.; Hehn, M.; Pierre, D.; Lacour, D.; Montaigne, F.; Lengaigne, G.; Robert, S.</AF>
   <BF></BF>
   <CA></CA>
   <TI>Finite tunnel magnetoresistance at the compensation point of Sm1-xGdxAl2, a ferromagnetic electrode with zero magnetization</TI>
   <SO>APPLIED PHYSICS LETTERS</SO>
   <SE></SE>
   <BS></BS>
   <LA>English</LA>
   <DT>Article</DT>
   <CT></CT>
   <CY></CY>
   <CL></CL>
   <SP></SP>
   <HO></HO>
   <DE></DE>
   <ID>TEMPERATURE-DEPENDENCE; JUNCTIONS; FILMS; BARRIER; MOMENT; OXIDE</ID>
   <AB>A tunnel magnetoresistance effect is observed in magnetic tunnel junctions with an original zero magnetization ferromagnetic electrode composed of Sm1-xGdxAl2. A finite tunnel magnetoresistance is measured when the Sm1-xGdxAl2 electrode is in a magnetic compensated state proving that Sm1-xGdxAl2 with zero magnetization is able to give rise to a spin-polarized current. The temperature dependence of tunnel magnetoresistance reveals that this effect is related to the relative orientation of spin contributions to magnetic moment in both electrodes and that the tunnel polarization of the Sm1-xGdxAl2 electrode is negative. (c) 2011 American Institute of Physics. [doi:10.1063/1.3597625]</AB>
   <C1>[Da Silva, M.; Dumesnil, K.; Dufour, C.; Hehn, M.; Pierre, D.; Lacour, D.; Montaigne, F.; Lengaigne, G.; Robert, S.] Nancy Univ, Inst Jean Lamour, UMR CNRS 7198, F-54506 Vandoeuvre Les Nancy, France</C1>
   <RP>Da Silva, M (reprint author), Nancy Univ, Inst Jean Lamour, UMR CNRS 7198, BP 239, F-54506 Vandoeuvre Les Nancy, France.</RP>
   <EM>dumesnil@lpm.u-nancy.fr</EM>
   <RI></RI>
   <OI></OI>
   <FU>La Region Lorraine</FU>
   <FX>The work presented in this letter is partly supported by La Region Lorraine. The authors acknowledge S. Suire for technical assistance.</FX>
   <CR></CR>
   <NR>25</NR>
   <TC>2</TC>
   <Z9>2</Z9>
   <PU>AMER INST PHYSICS</PU>
   <PI>MELVILLE</PI>
   <PA>CIRCULATION & FULFILLMENT DIV, 2 HUNTINGTON QUADRANGLE, STE 1 N O 1, MELVILLE, NY 11747-4501 USA</PA>
   <SN>0003-6951</SN>
   <EI></EI>
   <BN></BN>
   <J9>APPL PHYS LETT</J9>
   <JI>Appl. Phys. Lett.</JI>
   <PD>JUN 6</PD>
   <PY>2011</PY>
   <VL>98</VL>
   <IS>23</IS>
   <PN></PN>
   <SU></SU>
   <SI></SI>
   <MA></MA>
   <BP></BP>
   <EP></EP>
   <AR>232504</AR>
   <DI>10.1063/1.3597625</DI>
   <D2></D2>
   <PG>3</PG>
   <WC>Physics, Applied</WC>
   <SC>Physics</SC>
   <GA>777XQ</GA>
   <UT>WOS:000291658900045</UT>
   <PM></PM>
</bibliography>
