<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<bibliography>
   <PT>J</PT>
   <AU>Hauet, T; Piraux, L; Srivastava, SK; Antohe, VA; Lacour, D; Hehn, M; Montaigne, F; Schwenk, J; Marioni, MA; Hug, HJ; Hovorka, O; Berger, A; Mangin, S; Araujo, FA</AU>
   <BA></BA>
   <BE></BE>
   <GP></GP>
   <AF>Hauet, T.; Piraux, L.; Srivastava, S. K.; Antohe, V. A.; Lacour, D.; Hehn, M.; Montaigne, F.; Schwenk, J.; Marioni, M. A.; Hug, H. J.; Hovorka, O.; Berger, A.; Mangin, S.; Araujo, F. Abreu</AF>
   <BF></BF>
   <CA></CA>
   <TI>Reversal mechanism, switching field distribution, and dipolar frustrations in Co/Pt bit pattern media based on auto-assembled anodic alumina hexagonal nanobump arrays</TI>
   <SO>PHYSICAL REVIEW B</SO>
   <SE></SE>
   <BS></BS>
   <LA>English</LA>
   <DT>Article</DT>
   <CT></CT>
   <CY></CY>
   <CL></CL>
   <SP></SP>
   <HO></HO>
   <DE></DE>
   <ID>MAGNETIZATION REVERSAL; FILMS; MULTILAYERS; FABRICATION; PHASES</ID>
   <AB>We fabricated a perpendicularly magnetized bit pattern media using a hexagonally close-packed auto-assembled anodic alumina template with 100 nm and 50 nm periods by depositing a Co/Pt multilayer to form an ordered array of ferromagnetic nanodots, so-called nanobumps. We used Hall resistance measurements and magnetic force microscopy to characterize the dot-by-dot magnetization reversal mechanism under applied field. The role of interdot exchange coupling and dipolar coupling are investigated. Then we focus on separating the various origins of switching field distribution (SFD) in this system, namely dipolar interactions, intrinsic anisotropy distribution, and template packing faults. Finally we discuss the influence of triangular dipolar frustrations on the energy stability of demagnetized and half-switched states based on an Ising model, including local exchange coupling. The impact of SFD and lattice defects lines between misoriented ordered domains on the magnetic configurations is studied in detail.</AB>
   <C1>[Hauet, T.; Lacour, D.; Hehn, M.; Montaigne, F.; Mangin, S.] Univ Lorraine, Inst Jean Lamour, F-54506 Vandoeuvre Les Nancy, France; [Hauet, T.; Lacour, D.; Hehn, M.; Montaigne, F.; Mangin, S.] Univ Lorraine, CNRS, F-54506 Vandoeuvre Les Nancy, France; [Piraux, L.; Srivastava, S. K.; Antohe, V. A.; Araujo, F. Abreu] Catholic Univ Louvain, Inst Condensed Matter & Nanosci, B-1348 Louvain, Belgium; [Srivastava, S. K.] Amity Univ, Amity Inst Nanotechnol, Noida 201303, India; [Schwenk, J.; Hug, H. J.] Empa Swiss Fed Labs Mat Sci & Technol, CH-8600 Dubendorf, Switzerland; [Hug, H. J.] Univ Basel, Inst Phys, CH-4056 Basel, Switzerland; [Hovorka, O.] Univ Southampton, Fac Engn & Environm, Southampton SO17 1BJ, Hants, England; [Berger, A.] CIC NanoGUNE Consolider, E-20018 San Sebastian, Spain</C1>
   <RP>Hauet, T (reprint author), Univ Lorraine, Inst Jean Lamour, F-54506 Vandoeuvre Les Nancy, France.</RP>
   <EM></EM>
   <RI></RI>
   <OI></OI>
   <FU>Research Science Foundation of Belgium (FRS-FNRS)</FU>
   <FX>The authors thank S. Petit for help with numerical simulations. F.A.A. acknowledges the Research Science Foundation of Belgium (FRS-FNRS) for financial support (FRIA grant).</FX>
   <CR></CR>
   <NR>61</NR>
   <TC>1</TC>
   <Z9>1</Z9>
   <PU>AMER PHYSICAL SOC</PU>
   <PI>COLLEGE PK</PI>
   <PA>ONE PHYSICS ELLIPSE, COLLEGE PK, MD 20740-3844 USA</PA>
   <SN>1098-0121</SN>
   <EI>1550-235X</EI>
   <BN></BN>
   <J9>PHYS REV B</J9>
   <JI>Phys. Rev. B</JI>
   <PD>MAY 19</PD>
   <PY>2014</PY>
   <VL>89</VL>
   <IS>17</IS>
   <PN></PN>
   <SU></SU>
   <SI></SI>
   <MA></MA>
   <BP></BP>
   <EP></EP>
   <AR>174421</AR>
   <DI>10.1103/PhysRevB.89.174421</DI>
   <D2></D2>
   <PG>13</PG>
   <WC>Physics, Condensed Matter</WC>
   <SC>Physics</SC>
   <GA>AO4LD</GA>
   <UT>WOS:000341308600003</UT>
   <PM></PM>
</bibliography>
