<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<bibliography>
   <PT>J</PT>
   <AU>Briones, E; Cuadrado, A; Briones, J; de Leon, RD; Martinez-Anton, JC; McMurtry, S; Hehn, M; Montaigne, F; Alda, J; Gonzalez, FJ</AU>
   <BA></BA>
   <BE></BE>
   <GP></GP>
   <AF>Briones, Edgar; Cuadrado, Alexander; Briones, Joel; Diaz de Leon, Ramon; Carlos Martinez-Anton, Juan; McMurtry, Stefan; Hehn, Michel; Montaigne, Francois; Alda, Javier; Javier Gonzalez, Francisco</AF>
   <BF></BF>
   <CA></CA>
   <TI>Seebeck nanoantennas for the detection and characterization of infrared radiation</TI>
   <SO>OPTICS EXPRESS</SO>
   <SE></SE>
   <BS></BS>
   <LA>English</LA>
   <DT>Article</DT>
   <CT></CT>
   <CY></CY>
   <CL></CL>
   <SP></SP>
   <HO></HO>
   <DE></DE>
   <ID>ENERGY HARVESTING EFFICIENCY; DIPOLE ANTENNA; METAL DIODES; RECTENNAS</ID>
   <AB>Arrays of metallic thermocouples in the shape of spiral nanoantennas are proposed as infrared detectors, which use the thermoelectric properties of the metallic interfaces to generate electrical DC signals. The responsivity of these types of antennas is evaluated from both theoretical and numerical perspectives pointing out its potential as infrared sensors. Moreover, the same structures can be used to characterize the state of polarization of the optical near fields with a spatial resolution comparable to the wavelength. (C) 2014 Optical Society of America</AB>
   <C1>[Briones, Edgar; Javier Gonzalez, Francisco] Univ Autonoma San Luis Potosi, Coordinac Innovac & Aplicac Ciencia & Tecnol, Slp, Mexico; [Cuadrado, Alexander; Carlos Martinez-Anton, Juan; Alda, Javier] Univ Complutense Madrid, Appl Opt Complutense Grp, Fac Opt & Optometry, Madrid 28037, Spain; [Briones, Joel] Univ Santiago Chile USACH, Dept Fis, Santiago 9170124, Chile; [Diaz de Leon, Ramon] Inst Tecnol San Luis Potosi, Soledad De Graciano Sanc, Mexico; [McMurtry, Stefan; Hehn, Michel; Montaigne, Francois] Univ Lorraine, CNRS, Inst Jean Lamour, F-54506 Vandoeuvre Les Nancy, France</C1>
   <RP>Gonzalez, FJ (reprint author), Univ Autonoma San Luis Potosi, Coordinac Innovac & Aplicac Ciencia & Tecnol, Sierra Leona 550,Lomas 2a Secc, Slp, Mexico.</RP>
   <EM>javier.gonzalez@uaslp.mx</EM>
   <RI></RI>
   <OI></OI>
   <FU>project "Centro Mexicano de Innovacion en Energia Solar" from Fondo Sectorial CONACYT-Secretaria de Energia-Sustentabilidad Energetica"; CONACYT [CV-45809]; FONDECYT [3120059]; La Region Lorraine; Spanish Ministerio de Innovacion [ENE2009-013430]</FU>
   <FX>This work was supported by the project "Centro Mexicano de Innovacion en Energia Solar" from Fondo Sectorial CONACYT-Secretaria de Energia-Sustentabilidad Energetica", by CONACYT through postdoctoral grant CV-45809, by FONDECYT under project 3120059, by La Region Lorraine; and by Project ENE2009-013430 from the Spanish Ministerio de Innovacion.</FX>
   <CR></CR>
   <NR>37</NR>
   <TC>0</TC>
   <Z9>0</Z9>
   <PU>OPTICAL SOC AMER</PU>
   <PI>WASHINGTON</PI>
   <PA>2010 MASSACHUSETTS AVE NW, WASHINGTON, DC 20036 USA</PA>
   <SN>1094-4087</SN>
   <EI></EI>
   <BN></BN>
   <J9>OPT EXPRESS</J9>
   <JI>Opt. Express</JI>
   <PD>OCT 20</PD>
   <PY>2014</PY>
   <VL>22</VL>
   <IS>21</IS>
   <PN></PN>
   <SU></SU>
   <SI></SI>
   <MA></MA>
   <BP>A1538</BP>
   <EP>A1546</EP>
   <AR></AR>
   <DI>10.1364/OE.22.0A1538</DI>
   <D2></D2>
   <PG>9</PG>
   <WC>Optics</WC>
   <SC>Optics</SC>
   <GA>AS0ZF</GA>
   <UT>WOS:000344004600016</UT>
   <PM></PM>
</bibliography>
