<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<bibliography>
   <PT>J</PT>
   <AU>Herranz, D; Bonell, F; Gomez-Ibarlucea, A; Andrieu, S; Montaigne, F; Villar, R; Tiusan, C; Aliev, FG</AU>
   <BA></BA>
   <BE></BE>
   <GP></GP>
   <AF>Herranz, D.; Bonell, F.; Gomez-Ibarlucea, A.; Andrieu, S.; Montaigne, F.; Villar, R.; Tiusan, C.; Aliev, F. G.</AF>
   <BF></BF>
   <CA></CA>
   <TI>Strongly suppressed 1/f noise and enhanced magnetoresistance in epitaxial Fe-V/MgO/Fe magnetic tunnel junctions</TI>
   <SO>APPLIED PHYSICS LETTERS</SO>
   <SE></SE>
   <BS></BS>
   <LA>English</LA>
   <DT>Article</DT>
   <CT></CT>
   <CY></CY>
   <CL></CL>
   <SP></SP>
   <HO></HO>
   <DE>1; f noise; iron; iron alloys; magnesium compounds; tunnelling magnetoresistance; vanadium alloys</DE>
   <ID>ROOM-TEMPERATURE; MGO</ID>
   <AB>Alloying Fe electrodes with V, through reduced FeV/MgO interface mismatch in epitaxial magnetic tunnel junctions with MgO barriers, notably suppresses both nonmagnetic (parallel) and magnetic (antiparallel) state 1/f noise and enhances tunneling magnetoresistance. A comparative study of the room temperature electron transport and low frequency noise in Fe1-xVx/MgO/Fe and Fe/MgO/Fe1-xVx magnetic tunnel junctions with 0 inf x sup 0.25 reveals that V doping of the bottom electrode for x infs 0.1 reduces in nearly two orders of magnitude the normalized nonmagnetic and magnetic 1/f noise. We attribute the enhanced TMR and suppressed 1/f noise to strongly reduced misfit and dislocation density. (C) 2010 American Institute of Physics. [doi: 10.1063/1.3430064]</AB>
   <C1>[Herranz, D.; Gomez-Ibarlucea, A.; Villar, R.; Aliev, F. G.] Univ Autonoma Madrid, Dpto Fis Mat Condensada, CIII, E-28049 Madrid, Spain; [Bonell, F.; Andrieu, S.; Montaigne, F.; Tiusan, C.] Univ Nancy 1, CNRS, Inst Jean Lamour, F-54506 Vandoeuvre Les Nancy, France</C1>
   <RP>Aliev, FG (reprint author), Univ Autonoma Madrid, Dpto Fis Mat Condensada, CIII, E-28049 Madrid, Spain.</RP>
   <EM>farkhad.aliev@uam.es</EM>
   <RI>Tiusan, Coriolan/F-1564-2011; Bonell, Frederic/C-7209-2011</RI>
   <OI>Tiusan, Coriolan/0000-0003-1338-3867; </OI>
   <FU>Spanish MICINN [MAT2009-10139, CSD2007-00010, FR2009-0010]; CAM [P2009/MAT-1726]</FU>
   <FX>The work was supported by Spanish MICINN (Grant Nos. MAT2009-10139 and CSD2007-00010 and Integrated Action Project No. FR2009-0010) and CAM (Grant No. P2009/MAT-1726).</FX>
   <CR></CR>
   <NR>18</NR>
   <TC>14</TC>
   <Z9>17</Z9>
   <PU>AMER INST PHYSICS</PU>
   <PI>MELVILLE</PI>
   <PA>CIRCULATION et FULFILLMENT DIV, 2 HUNTINGTON QUADRANGLE, STE 1 N O 1, MELVILLE, NY 11747-4501 USA</PA>
   <SN>0003-6951</SN>
   <EI></EI>
   <BN></BN>
   <J9>APPL PHYS LETT</J9>
   <JI>Appl. Phys. Lett.</JI>
   <PD>MAY 17</PD>
   <PY>2010</PY>
   <VL>96</VL>
   <IS>20</IS>
   <PN></PN>
   <SU></SU>
   <SI></SI>
   <MA></MA>
   <BP></BP>
   <EP></EP>
   <AR>202501</AR>
   <DI>10.1063/1.3430064</DI>
   <D2></D2>
   <PG>3</PG>
   <WC>Physics, Applied</WC>
   <SC>Physics</SC>
   <GA>600FJ</GA>
   <UT>WOS:000277969700031</UT>
   <PM></PM>
</bibliography>
