<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<bibliography>
   <PT>J</PT>
   <AU>Alebrand, S; Bierbrauer, U; Hehn, M; Gottwald, M; Schmitt, O; Steil, D; Fullerton, EE; Mangin, S; Cinchetti, M; Aeschlimann, M</AU>
   <BA></BA>
   <BE></BE>
   <GP></GP>
   <AF>Alebrand, Sabine; Bierbrauer, Ute; Hehn, Michel; Gottwald, Matthias; Schmitt, Oliver; Steil, Daniel; Fullerton, Eric E.; Mangin, Stephane; Cinchetti, Mirko; Aeschlimann, Martin</AF>
   <BF></BF>
   <CA></CA>
   <TI>Subpicosecond magnetization dynamics in TbCo alloys</TI>
   <SO>PHYSICAL REVIEW B</SO>
   <SE></SE>
   <BS></BS>
   <LA>English</LA>
   <DT>Article</DT>
   <CT></CT>
   <CY></CY>
   <CL></CL>
   <SP></SP>
   <HO></HO>
   <DE></DE>
   <ID>TRANSITION-METAL ALLOYS; MAGNETOOPTICAL PROPERTIES; REVERSAL; FILMS; FE; CO</ID>
   <AB>Since the discovery of all-optical magnetization switching in rare-earth transition-metal alloys the underlying magnetization dynamics of multisublattice magnets has become a hot topic of modern magnetism. We studied the ultrafast magnetization dynamics in TbCo alloys as a function of the alloy composition and the laser fluence using either 800 nm or 400 nm probe pulses. Direct comparison between TbCo samples with different compositions for equal excitation conditions demonstrates that the magnetization dynamics of the Co sublattice strongly depends on the Tb concentration. For Tb32Co68 the magnetization of the sublattices can even transiently be reversed on a subpicosecond time scale.</AB>
   <C1>[Alebrand, Sabine; Bierbrauer, Ute; Schmitt, Oliver; Steil, Daniel; Cinchetti, Mirko; Aeschlimann, Martin] Univ Kaiserslautern, Dept Phys, D-67653 Kaiserslautern, Germany; [Alebrand, Sabine; Bierbrauer, Ute; Schmitt, Oliver; Steil, Daniel; Cinchetti, Mirko; Aeschlimann, Martin] Univ Kaiserslautern, Res Ctr OPTIMAS, D-67653 Kaiserslautern, Germany; [Hehn, Michel; Gottwald, Matthias; Mangin, Stephane] Univ Lorraine, Inst Jean Lamour, UMR CNRS 7198, Vandoeuvre Les Nancy, France; [Gottwald, Matthias; Fullerton, Eric E.; Mangin, Stephane] Univ Calif San Diego, Ctr Magnet Recording Res, La Jolla, CA 92093 USA</C1>
   <RP>Alebrand, S (reprint author), Univ Kaiserslautern, Dept Phys, D-67653 Kaiserslautern, Germany.</RP>
   <EM>cinchett@rhrk.uni-kl.de</EM>
   <RI>Fullerton, Eric/H-8445-2013; Cinchetti, Mirko/F-9769-2010</RI>
   <OI>Fullerton, Eric/0000-0002-4725-9509; Cinchetti, Mirko/0000-0003-0735-8921</OI>
   <FU>ANR [ANR-10-BLANC-1005]; European Project [OP2M FP7-IOF-2011-298060]; Region Lorraine</FU>
   <FX>This work was supported by the ANR Project No. ANR-10-BLANC-1005, "Friends," as well as the European Project No. OP2M FP7-IOF-2011-298060 and the Region Lorraine.</FX>
   <CR></CR>
   <NR>29</NR>
   <TC>2</TC>
   <Z9>2</Z9>
   <PU>AMER PHYSICAL SOC</PU>
   <PI>COLLEGE PK</PI>
   <PA>ONE PHYSICS ELLIPSE, COLLEGE PK, MD 20740-3844 USA</PA>
   <SN>1098-0121</SN>
   <EI>1550-235X</EI>
   <BN></BN>
   <J9>PHYS REV B</J9>
   <JI>Phys. Rev. B</JI>
   <PD>APR 3</PD>
   <PY>2014</PY>
   <VL>89</VL>
   <IS>14</IS>
   <PN></PN>
   <SU></SU>
   <SI></SI>
   <MA></MA>
   <BP></BP>
   <EP></EP>
   <AR>144404</AR>
   <DI>10.1103/PhysRevB.89.144404</DI>
   <D2></D2>
   <PG>7</PG>
   <WC>Physics, Condensed Matter</WC>
   <SC>Physics</SC>
   <GA>AE1WA</GA>
   <UT>WOS:000333760800002</UT>
   <PM></PM>
</bibliography>
