<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<bibliography>
   <PT>J</PT>
   <AU>Gopman, DB; Bedau, D; Mangin, S; Fullerton, EE; Katine, JA; Kent, AD</AU>
   <BA></BA>
   <BE></BE>
   <GP></GP>
   <AF>Gopman, D. B.; Bedau, D.; Mangin, S.; Fullerton, E. E.; Katine, J. A.; Kent, A. D.</AF>
   <BF></BF>
   <CA></CA>
   <TI>Bimodal switching field distributions in all-perpendicular spin-valve nanopillars</TI>
   <SO>JOURNAL OF APPLIED PHYSICS</SO>
   <SE></SE>
   <BS></BS>
   <LA>English</LA>
   <DT>Article</DT>
   <CT></CT>
   <CY></CY>
   <CL></CL>
   <SP></SP>
   <HO></HO>
   <DE></DE>
   <ID>MAGNETIZATION REVERSAL; ANISOTROPY</ID>
   <AB>Switching field measurements of the free layer element of 75 nm diameter spin-valve nanopillars reveal a bimodal distribution of switching fields at low temperatures (below 100 K). This result is inconsistent with a model of thermal activation over a single perpendicular anisotropy barrier. The correlation between antiparallel to parallel and parallel to antiparallel switching fields increases to nearly 50% at low temperatures. This reflects random fluctuation of the shift of the free layer hysteresis loop between two different magnitudes, which may originate from changes in the dipole field from the polarizing layer. The magnitude of the loop shift changes by 25% and is correlated to transitions of the spin-valve into an antiparallel configuration. (C) 2014 AIP Publishing LLC.</AB>
   <C1>[Gopman, D. B.; Kent, A. D.] NYU, Dept Phys, New York, NY 10003 USA; [Bedau, D.; Katine, J. A.] HGST San Jose Res Ctr, San Jose, CA 95135 USA; [Mangin, S.] Univ Lorraine, CNRS, UMR 7198, Inst Jean Lamour, Nancy, France; [Fullerton, E. E.] Univ Calif San Diego, CMRR, La Jolla, CA 92093 USA</C1>
   <RP>Gopman, DB (reprint author), NYU, Dept Phys, 4 Washington Pl, New York, NY 10003 USA.</RP>
   <EM>daniel.gopman@physics.nyu.edu</EM>
   <RI>Fullerton, Eric/H-8445-2013</RI>
   <OI>Fullerton, Eric/0000-0002-4725-9509</OI>
   <FU>NSF [DMR-1006575, NSF-DMR-1309202, DMR-1008654]; Partner University Fund (PUF) of the Embassy of France; European Project [OP2M FP7-IOF-2011-298060]; Region Lorraine;  [ANR-10-BLANC-1005]</FU>
   <FX>This research was supported at NYU by NSF Grant Nos. DMR-1006575 and NSF-DMR-1309202, as well as the Partner University Fund (PUF) of the Embassy of France. Research at UL supported by ANR-10-BLANC-1005 "Friends," the European Project (OP2M FP7-IOF-2011-298060) and the Region Lorraine. Work at UCSD supported by NSF Grant No. DMR-1008654.</FX>
   <CR></CR>
   <NR>15</NR>
   <TC>0</TC>
   <Z9>0</Z9>
   <PU>AMER INST PHYSICS</PU>
   <PI>MELVILLE</PI>
   <PA>CIRCULATION & FULFILLMENT DIV, 2 HUNTINGTON QUADRANGLE, STE 1 N O 1, MELVILLE, NY 11747-4501 USA</PA>
   <SN>0021-8979</SN>
   <EI>1089-7550</EI>
   <BN></BN>
   <J9>J APPL PHYS</J9>
   <JI>J. Appl. Phys.</JI>
   <PD>MAY 7</PD>
   <PY>2014</PY>
   <VL>115</VL>
   <IS>17</IS>
   <PN></PN>
   <SU></SU>
   <SI></SI>
   <MA></MA>
   <BP></BP>
   <EP></EP>
   <AR>17C707</AR>
   <DI>10.1063/1.4855019</DI>
   <D2></D2>
   <PG>3</PG>
   <WC>Physics, Applied</WC>
   <SC>Physics</SC>
   <GA>AG8BO</GA>
   <UT>WOS:000335643700341</UT>
   <PM></PM>
</bibliography>
