<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<bibliography>
   <PT>J</PT>
   <AU>Gottwald, M; Hehn, M; Lacour, D; Hauet, T; Montaigne, F; Mangin, S; Fischer, P; Im, MY; Berger, A</AU>
   <BA></BA>
   <BE></BE>
   <GP></GP>
   <AF>Gottwald, M.; Hehn, M.; Lacour, D.; Hauet, T.; Montaigne, F.; Mangin, S.; Fischer, P.; Im, M. -Y.; Berger, A.</AF>
   <BF></BF>
   <CA></CA>
   <TI>Asymmetric magnetization reversal in dipolarly coupled spin valve structures with perpendicular magnetic anisotropy</TI>
   <SO>PHYSICAL REVIEW B</SO>
   <SE></SE>
   <BS></BS>
   <LA>English</LA>
   <DT>Article</DT>
   <CT></CT>
   <CY></CY>
   <CL></CL>
   <SP></SP>
   <HO></HO>
   <DE></DE>
   <ID>FILMS; HYSTERESIS</ID>
   <AB>Magnetization reversal has been studied in a Co74Tb26/Cu/Co88Tb12 system, which is a perpendicularly magnetized ferrimagnetic bilayer separated by a nonmagnetic layer. The Co88Tb12 (soft) layer (SL) exhibits a switching field much lower than the Co74Tb26 (hard) layer (HL), which enabled us to study the magnetization reversal of the SL for different magnetic states of the HL. We found an asymmetric hysteresis loop for the SL, when the HL is not fully saturated. Using careful analysis of magnetic force microscopy measurements we conclude that the asymmetry originates from magnetic domains formed in the HL that affect the SL reversal. A simple model based on magnetic dipolar interaction between the two layers is found to be in good agreement with the experimental data.</AB>
   <C1>[Gottwald, M.; Hehn, M.; Lacour, D.; Hauet, T.; Montaigne, F.; Mangin, S.] Nancy Univ, CNRS, UMR 7198, Inst Jean Lamour, F-54506 Vandoeuvre Les Nancy, France; [Fischer, P.; Im, M. -Y.] Univ Calif Berkeley, Lawrence Berkeley Natl Lab, Ctr Xray Opt, Berkeley, CA 94720 USA; [Berger, A.] CIC nanoGUNE Consolider, E-20018 Donostia San Sebastian, Spain</C1>
   <RP>Gottwald, M (reprint author), Univ Calif San Diego, Ctr Magnet Recording Res, 9500 Gilman Dr, La Jolla, CA 92093 USA.</RP>
   <EM>mgottwald@ucsd.edu</EM>
   <RI>MSD, Nanomag/F-6438-2012; Fischer, Peter/A-3020-2010</RI>
   <OI>Fischer, Peter/0000-0002-9824-9343</OI>
   <FU>Basque Government [PI2009-17]; Spanish Ministry of Science and Education [MAT2009-07980]; ANR-NSF FRIENDS</FU>
   <FX>A.B. acknowledges funding from the Basque Government under Program No. PI2009-17 and the Spanish Ministry of Science and Education under Project No. MAT2009-07980. This work is supported by the ANR-NSF FRIENDS Project.</FX>
   <CR></CR>
   <NR>28</NR>
   <TC>4</TC>
   <Z9>4</Z9>
   <PU>AMER PHYSICAL SOC</PU>
   <PI>COLLEGE PK</PI>
   <PA>ONE PHYSICS ELLIPSE, COLLEGE PK, MD 20740-3844 USA</PA>
   <SN>1098-0121</SN>
   <EI></EI>
   <BN></BN>
   <J9>PHYS REV B</J9>
   <JI>Phys. Rev. B</JI>
   <PD>FEB 3</PD>
   <PY>2012</PY>
   <VL>85</VL>
   <IS>6</IS>
   <PN></PN>
   <SU></SU>
   <SI></SI>
   <MA></MA>
   <BP></BP>
   <EP></EP>
   <AR>064403</AR>
   <DI>10.1103/PhysRevB.85.064403</DI>
   <D2></D2>
   <PG>6</PG>
   <WC>Physics, Condensed Matter</WC>
   <SC>Physics</SC>
   <GA>887AD</GA>
   <UT>WOS:000299896400002</UT>
   <PM></PM>
</bibliography>
