<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<bibliography>
   <PT>J</PT>
   <AU>Briones, J; Montaigne, F; Hehn, M; Lacour, D; Childress, JR; Carey, MJ</AU>
   <BA></BA>
   <BE></BE>
   <GP></GP>
   <AF>Briones, Joel; Montaigne, Francois; Hehn, Michel; Lacour, Daniel; Childress, Jeffrey R.; Carey, Matthew J.</AF>
   <BF></BF>
   <CA></CA>
   <TI>Stochastic and complex depinning dynamics of magnetic domain walls</TI>
   <SO>PHYSICAL REVIEW B</SO>
   <SE></SE>
   <BS></BS>
   <LA>English</LA>
   <DT>Article</DT>
   <CT></CT>
   <CY></CY>
   <CL></CL>
   <SP></SP>
   <HO></HO>
   <DE></DE>
   <ID>REVERSAL</ID>
   <AB>We study the thermally induced depinning process of a single magnetic domain wall (DW) under applied field when the DW is trapped by a notch made in a nanowire shaped from a spin-valve multilayer with in-plane magnetization. In such devices depinning is typically a stochastic process and the depinning field distribution exhibits complex features. By analyzing simultaneously depinning field distributions and relaxation data, we observe two distinct sources of "complexity" in DW depinning processes: multiplicity in the DW structure and fundamental complexity in the depinning process.</AB>
   <C1>[Briones, Joel; Montaigne, Francois; Hehn, Michel; Lacour, Daniel] Nancy Univ, Inst Jean Lamour, CNRS, F-54506 Vandoeuvre Les Nancy, France; [Childress, Jeffrey R.; Carey, Matthew J.] Hitachi San Jose Res Ctr, San Jose, CA 95135 USA</C1>
   <RP>Briones, J (reprint author), Nancy Univ, Inst Jean Lamour, CNRS, BP 70239, F-54506 Vandoeuvre Les Nancy, France.</RP>
   <EM></EM>
   <RI></RI>
   <OI></OI>
   <FU>La Region Lorraine; CONACYT</FU>
   <FX>The work presented in this article is partly supported by La Region Lorraine. J.B. acknowledges support from CONACYT. The authors acknowledge G. Lengaigne for technical assistance.</FX>
   <CR></CR>
   <NR>22</NR>
   <TC>12</TC>
   <Z9>12</Z9>
   <PU>AMER PHYSICAL SOC</PU>
   <PI>COLLEGE PK</PI>
   <PA>ONE PHYSICS ELLIPSE, COLLEGE PK, MD 20740-3844 USA</PA>
   <SN>1098-0121</SN>
   <EI></EI>
   <BN></BN>
   <J9>PHYS REV B</J9>
   <JI>Phys. Rev. B</JI>
   <PD>FEB 10</PD>
   <PY>2011</PY>
   <VL>83</VL>
   <IS>6</IS>
   <PN></PN>
   <SU></SU>
   <SI></SI>
   <MA></MA>
   <BP></BP>
   <EP></EP>
   <AR>060401</AR>
   <DI>10.1103/PhysRevB.83.060401</DI>
   <D2></D2>
   <PG>4</PG>
   <WC>Physics, Condensed Matter</WC>
   <SC>Physics</SC>
   <GA>719GW</GA>
   <UT>WOS:000287191800001</UT>
   <PM></PM>
</bibliography>
