<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<bibliography>
   <PT>J</PT>
   <AU>Niklas, J; Bonin, A; Mangin, S; Bucher, J; Kopacz, S; Matz-Soja, M; Thiel, C; Gebhardt, R; Hofmann, U; Mauch, K</AU>
   <BA></BA>
   <BE></BE>
   <GP></GP>
   <AF>Niklas, Jens; Bonin, Anne; Mangin, Stefanie; Bucher, Joachim; Kopacz, Stephanie; Matz-Soja, Madlen; Thiel, Carlo; Gebhardt, Rolf; Hofmann, Ute; Mauch, Klaus</AF>
   <BF></BF>
   <CA></CA>
   <TI>Central energy metabolism remains robust in acute steatotic hepatocytes challenged by a high free fatty acid load</TI>
   <SO>BMB REPORTS</SO>
   <SE></SE>
   <BS></BS>
   <LA>English</LA>
   <DT>Article</DT>
   <CT></CT>
   <CY></CY>
   <CL></CL>
   <SP></SP>
   <HO></HO>
   <DE>Isotope labeling; Liver; Metabolic flux; Non-alcoholic fatty liver disease NAFLD; Steatosis; Transient C-13 MFA</DE>
   <ID>TRANSIENT C-13-LABELING EXPERIMENTS; MITOCHONDRIAL BETA-OXIDATION; LIVER-DISEASE; FLUX ANALYSIS; HEPATIC MITOCHONDRIAL; LIPID-METABOLISM; STEATOHEPATITIS; INSULIN; CELLS; IDENTIFICATION</ID>
   <AB>Overnutrition is one of the major causes of non-alcoholic fatty liver disease (NAFLD). NAFLD is characterized by an accumulation of lipids (triglycerides) in hepatocytes and is often accompanied by high plasma levels of free fatty acids (FFA). In this study, we compared the energy metabolism in acute steatotic and non-steatotic primary mouse hepatocytes. Acute steatosis was induced by pre-incubation with high concentrations of oleate and palmitate. Labeling experiments were conducted using [U-C-13(5),U-N-15(2)] glutamine. Metabolite concentrations and mass isotopomer distributions of intracellular metabolites were measured and applied for metabolic flux estimation using transient C-13 metabolic flux analysis. FFAs were efficiently taken up and almost completely incorporated into triglycerides (TAGs). In spite of high FFA uptake rates and the high synthesis rate of TAGs, central energy metabolism was not significantly changed in acute steatotic cells. Fatty acid beta-oxidation does not significantly contribute to the detoxification of FFAs under the applied conditions. [BMB Reports 2012; 45(7): 396-401]</AB>
   <C1>[Niklas, Jens; Bonin, Anne; Mangin, Stefanie; Bucher, Joachim; Mauch, Klaus] Insil Biotechnol AG, D-70563 Stuttgart, Germany; [Kopacz, Stephanie; Hofmann, Ute] Univ Tubingen, D-70376 Stuttgart, Germany; [Kopacz, Stephanie; Hofmann, Ute] Dr Margarete Fischer Bosch Inst Clin Pharmacol, D-70376 Stuttgart, Germany; [Matz-Soja, Madlen; Thiel, Carlo; Gebhardt, Rolf] Univ Leipzig, Fac Med, Inst Biochem, D-04103 Leipzig, Germany</C1>
   <RP>Niklas, J (reprint author), Insil Biotechnol AG, Meitnerstr 8, D-70563 Stuttgart, Germany.</RP>
   <EM>jens.niklas@insilico-biotechnology.com</EM>
   <RI></RI>
   <OI></OI>
   <FU>BMBF [0315762, 0315755, 0315735]; Robert-Bosch Foundation (Stuttgart, Germany)</FU>
   <FX>We acknowledge with thanks financial support from the BMBF project "Virtual Liver" (grants 0315762, 0315755, 0315735) and from the Robert-Bosch Foundation (Stuttgart, Germany). We also thank Tim Codanda for support, Sebastian Zellmer for valuable discussion, and Claudia Eser, Robert Karandi, Doris Mahn, and Monika Seiler for excellent technical assistance.</FX>
   <CR></CR>
   <NR>28</NR>
   <TC>4</TC>
   <Z9>4</Z9>
   <PU>KOREAN SOCIETY BIOCHEMISTRY & MOLECULAR BIOLOGY</PU>
   <PI>SEOUL</PI>
   <PA>KOREA SCIENCE & TECHNOLOGY CENTER, # 801,  635-4 , YEOKSAM-DONG, KANGNAM-KU, SEOUL, 135-703, SOUTH KOREA</PA>
   <SN>1976-6696</SN>
   <EI></EI>
   <BN></BN>
   <J9>BMB REP</J9>
   <JI>BMB Rep.</JI>
   <PD>JUL 31</PD>
   <PY>2012</PY>
   <VL>45</VL>
   <IS>7</IS>
   <PN></PN>
   <SU></SU>
   <SI></SI>
   <MA></MA>
   <BP>396</BP>
   <EP>401</EP>
   <AR></AR>
   <DI>10.5483/BMBRep.2012.45.7.070</DI>
   <D2></D2>
   <PG>6</PG>
   <WC>Biochemistry & Molecular Biology</WC>
   <SC>Biochemistry & Molecular Biology</SC>
   <GA>983RC</GA>
   <UT>WOS:000307135400003</UT>
   <PM>22831974</PM>
</bibliography>
