<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<bibliography>
   <PT>J</PT>
   <AU>Briones, J; Montaigne, F; Lacour, D; Lengaigne, G; Girod, S; Hehn, M</AU>
   <BA></BA>
   <BE></BE>
   <GP></GP>
   <AF>Briones, Joel; Montaigne, Francois; Lacour, Daniel; Lengaigne, Gwladys; Girod, Stephanie; Hehn, Michel</AF>
   <BF></BF>
   <CA></CA>
   <TI>Local Magnetic Anisotropy Induced by a Nano-Modulated Substrate and Application to Two-Dimensional Magnetic Sensors</TI>
   <SO>APPLIED PHYSICS EXPRESS</SO>
   <SE></SE>
   <BS></BS>
   <LA>English</LA>
   <DT>Article</DT>
   <CT></CT>
   <CY></CY>
   <CL></CL>
   <SP></SP>
   <HO></HO>
   <DE></DE>
   <ID>TUNNEL-JUNCTIONS; THIN-FILMS; FIELD; MAGNETORESISTANCE; LAYERS</ID>
   <AB>Topological modulation of magnetic thin films can induce a magnetic anisotropy of magnetostatic origin. In this paper, we report on the magnetic properties of NiFe layers deposited on wavy Si substrates. Without modulation, the film posses an intrinsic anisotropy. We unambiguously show that patterning the substrate overcomes the intrinsic anisotropy and establishes a new easy axis of magnetization. By choosing the patterning appropriately, orthogonal easy axes can be established at different locations of the same sample. We demonstrate the advantage of this approach in the fabrication of bidimensional magnetic sensors. (C) 2010 The Japan Society of Applied Physics</AB>
   <C1>[Briones, Joel; Montaigne, Francois; Lacour, Daniel; Lengaigne, Gwladys; Girod, Stephanie; Hehn, Michel] Nancy Univ, UPV Metz, Inst Jean Lamour, CNRS, F-54506 Vandoeuvre Les Nancy, France</C1>
   <RP>Lacour, D (reprint author), Nancy Univ, UPV Metz, Inst Jean Lamour, CNRS, Blvd Aiguillettes,BP 70239, F-54506 Vandoeuvre Les Nancy, France.</RP>
   <EM>daniel.lacour@ijl.nancy-universite.fr</EM>
   <RI></RI>
   <OI></OI>
   <FU>La Region Lorraine; CONACYT</FU>
   <FX>The work presented in this paper is partly supported by La Region Lorraine. J.B. acknowledges support from CONACYT. The authors also acknowledge M. Alnot for technical assistance and M. Fitzsimmons for critical reading of the manuscript.</FX>
   <CR></CR>
   <NR>15</NR>
   <TC>4</TC>
   <Z9>4</Z9>
   <PU>JAPAN SOC APPLIED PHYSICS</PU>
   <PI>TOKYO</PI>
   <PA>KUDAN-KITA BUILDING 5TH FLOOR, 1-12-3 KUDAN-KITA, CHIYODA-KU, TOKYO, 102-0073, JAPAN</PA>
   <SN>1882-0778</SN>
   <EI></EI>
   <BN></BN>
   <J9>APPL PHYS EXPRESS</J9>
   <JI>Appl. Phys. Express</JI>
   <PD></PD>
   <PY>2010</PY>
   <VL>3</VL>
   <IS>7</IS>
   <PN></PN>
   <SU></SU>
   <SI></SI>
   <MA></MA>
   <BP></BP>
   <EP></EP>
   <AR>073002</AR>
   <DI>10.1143/APEX.3.073002</DI>
   <D2></D2>
   <PG>3</PG>
   <WC>Physics, Applied</WC>
   <SC>Physics</SC>
   <GA>631YB</GA>
   <UT>WOS:000280385500018</UT>
   <PM></PM>
</bibliography>
