<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<bibliography>
   <PT>J</PT>
   <AU>McCord, J; Mangin, S</AU>
   <BA></BA>
   <BE></BE>
   <GP></GP>
   <AF>McCord, J.; Mangin, S.</AF>
   <BF></BF>
   <CA></CA>
   <TI>Separation of low- and high-temperature contributions to the exchange bias in Ni81Fe19-NiO thin films</TI>
   <SO>PHYSICAL REVIEW B</SO>
   <SE></SE>
   <BS></BS>
   <LA>English</LA>
   <DT>Article</DT>
   <CT></CT>
   <CY></CY>
   <CL></CL>
   <SP></SP>
   <HO></HO>
   <DE></DE>
   <ID>ASYMMETRIC MAGNETIZATION REVERSAL; COERCIVITY ENHANCEMENT; SPIN-GLASS; SYSTEMS; ANISOTROPY; NIO; MAGNETORESISTANCE; BILAYERS; CO/COO; MODEL</ID>
   <AB>The temperature and time dependence of exchange bias for as-deposited Ni81Fe19-NiO films is studied. Using various cooling and measurement protocols, different contributions to the exchange anisotropy are separated. Depending on the cooling procedure, a strong increase or a controlled reversal of sign of exchange bias field is achieved at lower temperatures far away from the antiferromagnetic blocking temperature. The behavior is explained in terms of antiferromagnetic grain instability and the influence of the interfacial spin structure, the latter freezing at very low temperatures.</AB>
   <C1>[McCord, J.] Univ Kiel, Inst Mat Sci, Kiel, Germany; [Mangin, S.] Univ Lorraine, CNRS, Inst Jean Lamour, UMR 7198, Vandoeuvre Les Nancy, France</C1>
   <RP>McCord, J (reprint author), Univ Kiel, Inst Mat Sci, Kiel, Germany.</RP>
   <EM></EM>
   <RI>McCord, Jeffrey/B-3234-2010</RI>
   <OI></OI>
   <FU>DAAD; ANR-MATETPRO COSMIQUE [11-RMNP-004]; Region Lorraine; German Research Foundation DFG's Heisenberg Programme [DFG MC9/9-1]</FU>
   <FX>J.M. thanks D. Elefant for help with the first low-temperature measurements, J.M. and S.M thank R. Kaltofen for the thin film deposition and T. Hauet and S. Suire for help with the magnetization measurements. Funding through the DAAD, the ANR-MATETPRO COSMIQUE 11-RMNP-004, and the Region Lorraine is highly acknowledged. J.M. is especially appreciative for funding through the German Research Foundation DFG's Heisenberg Programme (DFG MC9/9-1).</FX>
   <CR></CR>
   <NR>45</NR>
   <TC>3</TC>
   <Z9>3</Z9>
   <PU>AMER PHYSICAL SOC</PU>
   <PI>COLLEGE PK</PI>
   <PA>ONE PHYSICS ELLIPSE, COLLEGE PK, MD 20740-3844 USA</PA>
   <SN>1098-0121</SN>
   <EI></EI>
   <BN></BN>
   <J9>PHYS REV B</J9>
   <JI>Phys. Rev. B</JI>
   <PD>JUL 16</PD>
   <PY>2013</PY>
   <VL>88</VL>
   <IS>1</IS>
   <PN></PN>
   <SU></SU>
   <SI></SI>
   <MA></MA>
   <BP></BP>
   <EP></EP>
   <AR>014416</AR>
   <DI>10.1103/PhysRevB.88.014416</DI>
   <D2></D2>
   <PG>7</PG>
   <WC>Physics, Condensed Matter</WC>
   <SC>Physics</SC>
   <GA>183ZM</GA>
   <UT>WOS:000321855900004</UT>
   <PM></PM>
</bibliography>
