<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<bibliography>
   <PT>J</PT>
   <AU>Duluard, A; Negulescu, B; Bellouard, C; Hehn, M; Lacour, D; Lu, Y; Lengaigne, G; Montaigne, F; Robert, S; Suire, S; Tiusan, C</AU>
   <BA></BA>
   <BE></BE>
   <GP></GP>
   <AF>Duluard, A.; Negulescu, B.; Bellouard, C.; Hehn, M.; Lacour, D.; Lu, Y.; Lengaigne, G.; Montaigne, F.; Robert, S.; Suire, S.; Tiusan, C.</AF>
   <BF></BF>
   <CA></CA>
   <TI>Fe/MgO/Fe (100) textured tunnel junctions exhibiting spin polarization features of single crystal junctions</TI>
   <SO>APPLIED PHYSICS LETTERS</SO>
   <SE></SE>
   <BS></BS>
   <LA>English</LA>
   <DT>Article</DT>
   <CT></CT>
   <CY></CY>
   <CL></CL>
   <SP></SP>
   <HO></HO>
   <DE></DE>
   <ID>ROOM-TEMPERATURE; MAGNETORESISTANCE</ID>
   <AB>Crystallographic and spin polarized transport properties of (100) textured and (100) epitaxial Fe/MgO/Fe magnetic tunnel junctions are compared. Strong similarities in the transport properties show that structural coherence and magnetic quality at the 25 nm grain scale in textured junctions are sufficient to issue signatures of the spin polarized transport specific to a single crystal junction. This demonstrates that the lateral coherence of the Bloch tunneling wave function is identically limited in both systems. Our analysis leads to model the textured tunnel junction as a juxtaposition of nanometer sized single crystal junctions, placed in parallel. (C) 2012 American Institute of Physics. [doi:10.1063/1.3687174]</AB>
   <C1>[Duluard, A.; Bellouard, C.; Hehn, M.; Lacour, D.; Lu, Y.; Lengaigne, G.; Montaigne, F.; Robert, S.; Suire, S.; Tiusan, C.] Nancy Univ, CNRS, Inst Jean Lamour, F-54506 Vandoeuvre Les Nancy, France; [Negulescu, B.] Univ Tours, UMR CNRS CEA 6157, LEMA, F-37200 Tours, France; [Tiusan, C.] Tech Univ Cluj Napoca, Mat Sci Lab, Cluj Napoca, Romania</C1>
   <RP>Duluard, A (reprint author), Nancy Univ, CNRS, Inst Jean Lamour, BP 70239, F-54506 Vandoeuvre Les Nancy, France.</RP>
   <EM>coriolan.tiusan@phys.utcluj.ro</EM>
   <RI>Tiusan, Coriolan/F-1564-2011; Lu, Yuan/M-9239-2014</RI>
   <OI>Tiusan, Coriolan/0000-0003-1338-3867; Lu, Yuan/0000-0003-3337-8205</OI>
   <FU>SPINCHAT [ANR-07-BLAN-341]; POS CCE [574, SMIS-CSNR 12467]</FU>
   <FX>C. Tiusan acknowledges the SPINCHAT project ANR-07-BLAN-341 and POS CCE ID. 574, code SMIS-CSNR 12467.</FX>
   <CR></CR>
   <NR>15</NR>
   <TC>1</TC>
   <Z9>1</Z9>
   <PU>AMER INST PHYSICS</PU>
   <PI>MELVILLE</PI>
   <PA>CIRCULATION & FULFILLMENT DIV, 2 HUNTINGTON QUADRANGLE, STE 1 N O 1, MELVILLE, NY 11747-4501 USA</PA>
   <SN>0003-6951</SN>
   <EI></EI>
   <BN></BN>
   <J9>APPL PHYS LETT</J9>
   <JI>Appl. Phys. Lett.</JI>
   <PD>FEB 13</PD>
   <PY>2012</PY>
   <VL>100</VL>
   <IS>7</IS>
   <PN></PN>
   <SU></SU>
   <SI></SI>
   <MA></MA>
   <BP></BP>
   <EP></EP>
   <AR>072408</AR>
   <DI>10.1063/1.3687174</DI>
   <D2></D2>
   <PG>4</PG>
   <WC>Physics, Applied</WC>
   <SC>Physics</SC>
   <GA>894OR</GA>
   <UT>WOS:000300436800048</UT>
   <PM></PM>
</bibliography>
﻿JGopman, DB; Bedau, D; Mangin, S; Lambert, CH; Fullerton, EE; Katine, JA; Kent, ADGopman, D. B.; Bedau, D.; Mangin, S.; Lambert, C. H.; Fullerton, E. E.; Katine, J. A.; Kent, A. D.Asymmetric switching behavior in perpendicularly magnetized spin-valve nanopillars due to the polarizer dipole fieldAPPLIED PHYSICS LETTERSEnglishArticleinterface magnetism; lithography; magnetic switching; magnetic transitions; magnetisation; nanomagnetics; spin valvesDEPENDENCE; ANISOTROPY; JUNCTION; TIMEWe report the free layer switching field distributions of spin-valve nanopillars with perpendicular magnetization. While the distributions are consistent with a thermal activation model, they show a strong asymmetry between the parallel to antiparallel and the reverse transition, with energy barriers more than 50% higher for the parallel to antiparallel transitions. The inhomogeneous dipolar field from the polarizer is demonstrated to be at the origin of this symmetry breaking. Interestingly, the symmetry is restored for devices with a lithographically defined notch pair removed from the midpoint of the pillar cross-section along the ellipse long axis. These results have important implications for the thermal stability of perpendicular magnetized magnetic random access memory bit cells. (C) 2012 American Institute of Physics. [doi: 10.1063/1.3681792][Gopman, D. B.; Bedau, D.; Kent, A. D.] NYU, Dept Phys, New York, NY 10003 USA; [Mangin, S.; Lambert, C. H.] Nancy Univ, UMR CNRS 7198, Inst Jean Lamour, Vandoeuvre Les Nancy, France; [Fullerton, E. E.] Univ Calif San Diego, CMRR, La Jolla, CA 92093 USA; [Katine, J. A.] Hitachi GST, San Jose Res Ctr, San Jose, CA 95135 USAGopman, DB (reprint author), NYU, Dept Phys, 4 Washington Pl, New York, NY 10003 USA.db137@nyu.eduFullerton, Eric/H-8445-2013Fullerton, Eric/0000-0002-4725-9509NYU by NSF [DMR-1006575]; UCSD [DMR-1008654]; Embassy of FranceThis research was supported at NYU by NSF Grant DMR-1006575 and at UCSD by DMR-1008654 as well as the Partner University Fund (PUF) of the Embassy of France.1899AMER INST PHYSICSMELVILLECIRCULATION & FULFILLMENT DIV, 2 HUNTINGTON QUADRANGLE, STE 1 N O 1, MELVILLE, NY 11747-4501 USA0003-6951APPL PHYS LETTAppl. Phys. Lett.FEB 62012100606240410.1063/1.36817923Physics, AppliedPhysics891JWWOS:000300214000047