<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<bibliography>
   <PT>J</PT>
   <AU>Andrieu, S; Bonell, F; Hauet, T; Montaigne, F; Calmels, L; Snoeck, E; Lefevre, P; Bertran, F</AU>
   <BA></BA>
   <BE></BE>
   <GP></GP>
   <AF>Andrieu, S.; Bonell, F.; Hauet, T.; Montaigne, F.; Calmels, L.; Snoeck, E.; Lefevre, P.; Bertran, F.</AF>
   <BF></BF>
   <CA></CA>
   <TI>Magnetotransport in MgO-based magnetic tunnel junctions grown by molecular beam epitaxy (invited)</TI>
   <SO>JOURNAL OF APPLIED PHYSICS</SO>
   <SE></SE>
   <BS></BS>
   <LA>English</LA>
   <DT>Article</DT>
   <CT></CT>
   <CY></CY>
   <CL></CL>
   <SP></SP>
   <HO></HO>
   <DE></DE>
   <ID>ROOM-TEMPERATURE; MAGNETORESISTANCE</ID>
   <AB>The strong impact of molecular beam epitaxy growth and Synchrotron Radiation characterization tools in the understanding of fundamental issues in nanomagnetism and spintronics is illustrated through the example of fully epitaxial MgO-based Magnetic Tunnel Junctions (MTJs). If ab initio calculations predict very high tunnel magnetoresistance (TMR) in such devices, some discrepancy between theory and experiments still exists. The influence of imperfections in real systems has thus to be considered like surface contaminations, structural defects, unexpected electronic states, etc. The influence of possible oxygen contamination at the Fe/MgO(001) interface is thus studied, and is shown to be not so detrimental to TMR as predicted by ab initio calculations. On the contrary, the decrease of dislocations density in the MgO barrier of MTJs using Fe1-xVx electrodes is shown to significantly increase TMR. Finally, unexpected transport properties in Fe1-XCox/MgO/Fe1-XCox (001) are presented. With the help of spin and symmetry resolved photoemission and ab initio calculation, the TMR decrease for Co content higher than 25% is shown to come from the existence of an interface state and the shift of the empty Delta 1 minority spin state towards the Fermi level. (C) 2014 AIP Publishing LLC.</AB>
   <C1>[Andrieu, S.; Bonell, F.; Hauet, T.; Montaigne, F.] Nancy Univ, CNRS, Inst Jean Lamour, F-54506 Vandoeuvre Les Nancy, France; [Calmels, L.; Snoeck, E.] CNRS, CEMES, F-31055 Toulouse, France; [Calmels, L.; Snoeck, E.] Toulouse Univ, F-31055 Toulouse, France; [Lefevre, P.; Bertran, F.] CNRS, Synchrotron SOLEIL, F-91192 Gif Sur Yvette, France</C1>
   <RP>Andrieu, S (reprint author), Nancy Univ, CNRS, Inst Jean Lamour, Bd Aiguillettes,BP239, F-54506 Vandoeuvre Les Nancy, France.</RP>
   <EM>stephane.andrieu@univ-lorraine.fr</EM>
   <RI></RI>
   <OI></OI>
   <FU></FU>
   <FX></FX>
   <CR></CR>
   <NR>30</NR>
   <TC>0</TC>
   <Z9>0</Z9>
   <PU>AMER INST PHYSICS</PU>
   <PI>MELVILLE</PI>
   <PA>CIRCULATION & FULFILLMENT DIV, 2 HUNTINGTON QUADRANGLE, STE 1 N O 1, MELVILLE, NY 11747-4501 USA</PA>
   <SN>0021-8979</SN>
   <EI>1089-7550</EI>
   <BN></BN>
   <J9>J APPL PHYS</J9>
   <JI>J. Appl. Phys.</JI>
   <PD>MAY 7</PD>
   <PY>2014</PY>
   <VL>115</VL>
   <IS>17</IS>
   <PN></PN>
   <SU></SU>
   <SI></SI>
   <MA></MA>
   <BP></BP>
   <EP></EP>
   <AR>172610</AR>
   <DI>10.1063/1.4869824</DI>
   <D2></D2>
   <PG>6</PG>
   <WC>Physics, Applied</WC>
   <SC>Physics</SC>
   <GA>AG8BO</GA>
   <UT>WOS:000335643700579</UT>
   <PM></PM>
</bibliography>
