<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<bibliography>
   <PT>J</PT>
   <AU>Louis, D; Lytvynenko, I; Hauet, T; Lacour, D; Hehn, M; Andrieu, S; Montaigne, F</AU>
   <BA></BA>
   <BE></BE>
   <GP></GP>
   <AF>Louis, D.; Lytvynenko, Ia.; Hauet, T.; Lacour, D.; Hehn, M.; Andrieu, S.; Montaigne, F.</AF>
   <BF></BF>
   <CA></CA>
   <TI>Interfaces anisotropy in single crystal V/Fe/V trilayer</TI>
   <SO>JOURNAL OF MAGNETISM AND MAGNETIC MATERIALS</SO>
   <SE></SE>
   <BS></BS>
   <LA>English</LA>
   <DT>Article</DT>
   <CT></CT>
   <CY></CY>
   <CL></CL>
   <SP></SP>
   <HO></HO>
   <DE>Nanomagnetism; Interface anisotropy; Epitaxial films; Single crystal Iron; Magnetization</DE>
   <ID>MAGNETIC-ANISOTROPY; ROOM-TEMPERATURE; SUPERLATTICES; IRON</ID>
   <AB>The value and sign of V/Fe interface anisotropy are investigated. Epitaxial V/Fe/V/Au layers with different iron thicknesses were grown on single crystalline (001) MgO substrate by ultra high vacuum molecular beam epitaxy. Magnetometry was used to measure magnetization and out anisotropy field. From these values, we quantify the number of dead layers due to V/Fe or Fe/V interfaces, and compare it with the literature. We deduce that dead layers occur mostly at the bottom V/Fe interface. An average value for V/Fe and Fe/V interface anisotropy around 0 +/- 0.1 erg/cm(2) (mJ/m(2)) was thus deduced. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</AB>
   <C1>[Louis, D.; Hauet, T.; Lacour, D.; Hehn, M.; Andrieu, S.; Montaigne, F.] Univ Lorraine, UMR CNRS 7198, Inst Jean Lamour, F-54506 Vandoeuvre Les Nancy, France; [Lytvynenko, Ia.] Sumy State Univ, UA-40007 Sumy, Ukraine</C1>
   <RP>Hauet, T (reprint author), Univ Lorraine, UMR CNRS 7198, Inst Jean Lamour, F-54506 Vandoeuvre Les Nancy, France.</RP>
   <EM>thomas.hauet@univ-lorraine.fr</EM>
   <RI></RI>
   <OI></OI>
   <FU>Region Lorraine; French Agence Nationale de la Recherche [ANR-2010-BLANC-1006, ANR-2012-BS04-0009]</FU>
   <FX>Authors thank T. Ferte and L. Pasquier for helping with growth experiments. This work was supported by the Region Lorraine and by the French Agence Nationale de la Recherche, ANR-2010-BLANC-1006 (Elecmade) and ANR-2012-BS04-0009 (Frustrated).</FX>
   <CR></CR>
   <NR>18</NR>
   <TC>0</TC>
   <Z9>0</Z9>
   <PU>ELSEVIER SCIENCE BV</PU>
   <PI>AMSTERDAM</PI>
   <PA>PO BOX 211, 1000 AE AMSTERDAM, NETHERLANDS</PA>
   <SN>0304-8853</SN>
   <EI>1873-4766</EI>
   <BN></BN>
   <J9>J MAGN MAGN MATER</J9>
   <JI>J. Magn. Magn. Mater.</JI>
   <PD>DEC</PD>
   <PY>2014</PY>
   <VL>372</VL>
   <IS></IS>
   <PN></PN>
   <SU></SU>
   <SI></SI>
   <MA></MA>
   <BP>233</BP>
   <EP>235</EP>
   <AR></AR>
   <DI>10.1016/j.jmmm.2014.07.018</DI>
   <D2></D2>
   <PG>3</PG>
   <WC>Materials Science, Multidisciplinary; Physics, Condensed Matter</WC>
   <SC>Materials Science; Physics</SC>
   <GA>AO6GI</GA>
   <UT>WOS:000341447900035</UT>
   <PM></PM>
</bibliography>
