<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<bibliography>
   <PT>J</PT>
   <AU>Pigeau, B; Hahn, C; de Loubens, G; Naletov, VV; Klein, O; Mitsuzuka, K; Lacour, D; Hehn, M; Andrieu, S; Montaigne, F</AU>
   <BA></BA>
   <BE></BE>
   <GP></GP>
   <AF>Pigeau, B.; Hahn, C.; de Loubens, G.; Naletov, V. V.; Klein, O.; Mitsuzuka, K.; Lacour, D.; Hehn, M.; Andrieu, S.; Montaigne, F.</AF>
   <BF></BF>
   <CA></CA>
   <TI>Measurement of the Dynamical Dipolar Coupling in a Pair of Magnetic Nanodisks Using a Ferromagnetic Resonance Force Microscope</TI>
   <SO>PHYSICAL REVIEW LETTERS</SO>
   <SE></SE>
   <BS></BS>
   <LA>English</LA>
   <DT>Article</DT>
   <CT></CT>
   <CY></CY>
   <CL></CL>
   <SP></SP>
   <HO></HO>
   <DE></DE>
   <ID>ARBITRARY SHAPE; MODES</ID>
   <AB>We perform a spectroscopic study of the collective spin-wave dynamics occurring in a pair of magnetic nanodisks coupled by the magnetodipolar interaction. We take advantage of the stray field gradient produced by the magnetic tip of a ferromagnetic resonance force microscope to continuously tune and detune the relative resonance frequencies between two adjacent nano-objects. This reveals the anticrossing and hybridization of the spin-wave modes in the pair. At the exact tuning, the measured frequency splitting between the binding and antibinding modes corresponds to the strength of the dynamical dipolar coupling Omega. This accurate ferromagnetic resonance force microscope determination of Omega is measured versus the separation between the nanodisks. It agrees quantitatively with calculations of the expected dynamical magnetodipolar interaction in our sample.</AB>
   <C1>[Pigeau, B.; Hahn, C.; de Loubens, G.; Naletov, V. V.; Klein, O.] CEA Saclay, Serv Phys Etat Condense, CNRS, URA 2464, F-91191 Gif Sur Yvette, France; [Mitsuzuka, K.; Lacour, D.; Hehn, M.; Andrieu, S.; Montaigne, F.] Univ Lorraine, Inst Jean Lamour, CNRS, UMR 7198, F-54506 Nancy, France</C1>
   <RP>Pigeau, B (reprint author), CEA Saclay, Serv Phys Etat Condense, CNRS, URA 2464, F-91191 Gif Sur Yvette, France.</RP>
   <EM>benjamin.pigeau@cea.fr</EM>
   <RI>Naletov, Vladimir/L-5610-2013</RI>
   <OI></OI>
   <FU>French Grant VOICE [ANR-09-NANO-006-01]; French Grant MARVEL [ANR-2010-JCJC-0410-01]</FU>
   <FX>This research work was partially supported by the French Grants VOICE ANR-09-NANO-006-01 and MARVEL ANR-2010-JCJC-0410-01.</FX>
   <CR></CR>
   <NR>28</NR>
   <TC>7</TC>
   <Z9>7</Z9>
   <PU>AMER PHYSICAL SOC</PU>
   <PI>COLLEGE PK</PI>
   <PA>ONE PHYSICS ELLIPSE, COLLEGE PK, MD 20740-3844 USA</PA>
   <SN>0031-9007</SN>
   <EI></EI>
   <BN></BN>
   <J9>PHYS REV LETT</J9>
   <JI>Phys. Rev. Lett.</JI>
   <PD>DEC 10</PD>
   <PY>2012</PY>
   <VL>109</VL>
   <IS>24</IS>
   <PN></PN>
   <SU></SU>
   <SI></SI>
   <MA></MA>
   <BP></BP>
   <EP></EP>
   <AR>247602</AR>
   <DI>10.1103/PhysRevLett.109.247602</DI>
   <D2></D2>
   <PG>5</PG>
   <WC>Physics, Multidisciplinary</WC>
   <SC>Physics</SC>
   <GA>050QE</GA>
   <UT>WOS:000312068300037</UT>
   <PM>23368378</PM>
</bibliography>
