<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<bibliography>
   <PT>J</PT>
   <AU>Berger, A; Mangin, S; McCord, J; Hellwig, O; Fullerton, EE</AU>
   <BA></BA>
   <BE></BE>
   <GP></GP>
   <AF>Berger, A.; Mangin, S.; McCord, J.; Hellwig, O.; Fullerton, E. E.</AF>
   <BF></BF>
   <CA></CA>
   <TI>Cumulative minor loop growth in Co/Pt and Co/Pd multilayers</TI>
   <SO>PHYSICAL REVIEW B</SO>
   <SE></SE>
   <BS></BS>
   <LA>English</LA>
   <DT>Article</DT>
   <CT></CT>
   <CY></CY>
   <CL></CL>
   <SP></SP>
   <HO></HO>
   <DE></DE>
   <ID>SWITCHING FIELD DISTRIBUTIONS; PERPENDICULAR ANISOTROPY; MAGNETIZATION-REVERSAL; FILMS; HYSTERESIS; MEDIA; DYNAMICS; SYSTEMS; MODELS</ID>
   <AB>The behavior of minor hysteresis loops in perpendicular anisotropy [Co/Pt] and [Co/Pd] multilayers has been investigated. Upon applying a succession of identical magnetic field cycles, we observe a very substantial cumulative growth of the minor loop area. For the [Co/Pt] multilayers this effect only saturates near complete magnetization reversal while the behavior is slightly more limited for [Co/Pd] multilayers. We also find this cumulative growth to occur even if the minor loop field cycles are made asymmetric by means of a positive bias field. The cumulative behavior persists up to a sample-dependent threshold value above which this effect disappears. In all samples, the cumulative minor loop growth is correlated with a small reduction in the maximum magnetization value in each cycle. Magneto-optical Kerr microscopy studies correlate the minor loop growth with the memory and cumulative expansion of lateral domain cycling. All experimental observations can be consistently explained as an accumulation of small nucleation domains that aid subsequent reversals and facilitate the cumulative minor loop growth.</AB>
   <C1>[Berger, A.] CIC NanoGUNE Consolider, E-20018 Donostia San Sebastian, Spain; [Mangin, S.] Nancy Univ, CNRS, IJL, UMR 7198, F-54506 Vandoeuvre Les Nancy, France; [McCord, J.] Forschungszentrum Dresden Rossendorf, Inst Ion Beam Phys & Mat Res, D-01328 Dresden, Germany; [Hellwig, O.] Hitachi Global Storage Technol, San Jose Res Ctr, San Jose, CA 95135 USA; [Fullerton, E. E.] Univ Calif San Diego, Ctr Magnet Recording Res, La Jolla, CA 92093 USA</C1>
   <RP>Berger, A (reprint author), CIC NanoGUNE Consolider, E-20018 Donostia San Sebastian, Spain.</RP>
   <EM></EM>
   <RI>McCord, Jeffrey/B-3234-2010; Fullerton, Eric/H-8445-2013</RI>
   <OI>Fullerton, Eric/0000-0002-4725-9509</OI>
   <FU>Department of Industry, Trade, and Tourism of the Basque Government [IE06-172]; Department of Education, Universities, and Research of the Basque Government [PI2009-17]; Provincial Council of Gipuzkoa; Spanish Ministry of Science and Education [CSD2006-53, MAT2009-07980]</FU>
   <FX>A.B. acknowledges funding from the Department of Industry, Trade, and Tourism of the Basque Government under Program No. IE06-172, the Department of Education, Universities, and Research of the Basque Government under Program No. PI2009-17, and the Provincial Council of Gipuzkoa, as well as from the Spanish Ministry of Science and Education under Projects No. CSD2006-53 and No. MAT2009-07980. J.M. thanks N. Martin for experimental help with the magneto-optical microscopy setup.</FX>
   <CR></CR>
   <NR>39</NR>
   <TC>16</TC>
   <Z9>16</Z9>
   <PU>AMER PHYSICAL SOC</PU>
   <PI>COLLEGE PK</PI>
   <PA>ONE PHYSICS ELLIPSE, COLLEGE PK, MD 20740-3844 USA</PA>
   <SN>1098-0121</SN>
   <EI></EI>
   <BN></BN>
   <J9>PHYS REV B</J9>
   <JI>Phys. Rev. B</JI>
   <PD>SEP 20</PD>
   <PY>2010</PY>
   <VL>82</VL>
   <IS>10</IS>
   <PN></PN>
   <SU></SU>
   <SI></SI>
   <MA></MA>
   <BP></BP>
   <EP></EP>
   <AR>104423</AR>
   <DI>10.1103/PhysRevB.82.104423</DI>
   <D2></D2>
   <PG>9</PG>
   <WC>Physics, Condensed Matter</WC>
   <SC>Physics</SC>
   <GA>652KU</GA>
   <UT>WOS:000282006100004</UT>
   <PM></PM>
</bibliography>
