<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<bibliography>
   <PT>J</PT>
   <AU>Torrejon, J; Malinowski, G; Pelloux, M; Weil, R; Thiaville, A; Curiale, J; Lacour, D; Montaigne, F; Hehn, M</AU>
   <BA></BA>
   <BE></BE>
   <GP></GP>
   <AF>Torrejon, J.; Malinowski, G.; Pelloux, M.; Weil, R.; Thiaville, A.; Curiale, J.; Lacour, D.; Montaigne, F.; Hehn, M.</AF>
   <BF></BF>
   <CA></CA>
   <TI>Unidirectional Thermal Effects in Current-Induced Domain Wall Motion</TI>
   <SO>PHYSICAL REVIEW LETTERS</SO>
   <SE></SE>
   <BS></BS>
   <LA>English</LA>
   <DT>Article</DT>
   <CT></CT>
   <CY></CY>
   <CL></CL>
   <SP></SP>
   <HO></HO>
   <DE></DE>
   <ID>AMORPHOUS FERROMAGNETIC MATERIALS; SPIN CALORITRONICS; WAVE</ID>
   <AB>We report experimental evidence of thermal effects on the displacement of vortex walls in NiFe nanostrips. With the use of nanosecond current pulses, a unidirectional motion of the magnetic domain walls towards the hotter part of the nanostrips is observed, in addition to current-induced domain wall motion. By tuning the heat dissipation in the samples and modeling the heat diffusion, we conclude that this unidirectional motion can only be explained by the presence of a temperature profile along the nanostrip. A quantitative analysis of the experiments shows that, on top of the classical thermodynamic pressure on the domain wall, another force, probably the magnonic spin Seebeck effect, is displacing the domain walls.</AB>
   <C1>[Torrejon, J.; Malinowski, G.; Pelloux, M.; Weil, R.; Thiaville, A.; Curiale, J.] Univ Paris 11, CNRS, UMR 8502, Lab Phys Solides, F-91405 Orsay, France; [Curiale, J.] Comis Nacl Energia Atom, Ctr Atom Bariloche, Consejo Nacl Invest Cient & Tecn, RA-8400 San Carlos De Bariloche, Rio Negro, Argentina; [Lacour, D.; Montaigne, F.; Hehn, M.] Univ Nancy 1, Inst Jean Lamour, F-54506 Vandoeuvre Les Nancy, France; [Curiale, J.] Comis Nacl Energia Atom, Inst Balseiro, RA-8400 San Carlos De Bariloche, Rio Negro, Argentina; [Curiale, J.] Univ Nacl Cuyo, RA-8400 San Carlos De Bariloche, Rio Negro, Argentina</C1>
   <RP>Torrejon, J (reprint author), Univ Paris 11, CNRS, UMR 8502, Lab Phys Solides, F-91405 Orsay, France.</RP>
   <EM>torrejon@lps.u-psud.fr</EM>
   <RI></RI>
   <OI></OI>
   <FU>European Community [251887]; French Agence Nationale de la Recherche [HYFONT ANR-09-NANO-002]</FU>
   <FX>J. T. acknowledges the support by the European Community's Seventh Framework Programme, through an individual IEF Marie Curie fellowship (CIDWM-nanostrips, No. 251887). The research at LPS was partially supported by the French Agence Nationale de la Recherche, Project No. HYFONT ANR-09-NANO-002.</FX>
   <CR></CR>
   <NR>32</NR>
   <TC>10</TC>
   <Z9>10</Z9>
   <PU>AMER PHYSICAL SOC</PU>
   <PI>COLLEGE PK</PI>
   <PA>ONE PHYSICS ELLIPSE, COLLEGE PK, MD 20740-3844 USA</PA>
   <SN>0031-9007</SN>
   <EI></EI>
   <BN></BN>
   <J9>PHYS REV LETT</J9>
   <JI>Phys. Rev. Lett.</JI>
   <PD>SEP 4</PD>
   <PY>2012</PY>
   <VL>109</VL>
   <IS>10</IS>
   <PN></PN>
   <SU></SU>
   <SI></SI>
   <MA></MA>
   <BP></BP>
   <EP></EP>
   <AR>106601</AR>
   <DI>10.1103/PhysRevLett.109.106601</DI>
   <D2></D2>
   <PG>5</PG>
   <WC>Physics, Multidisciplinary</WC>
   <SC>Physics</SC>
   <GA>999FV</GA>
   <UT>WOS:000308295700013</UT>
   <PM>23005312</PM>
</bibliography>
