<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<bibliography>
   <PT>J</PT>
   <AU>Chioar, IA; Rougemaille, N; Grimm, A; Fruchart, O; Wagner, E; Hehn, M; Lacour, D; Montaigne, F; Canals, B</AU>
   <BA></BA>
   <BE></BE>
   <GP></GP>
   <AF>Chioar, I. A.; Rougemaille, N.; Grimm, A.; Fruchart, O.; Wagner, E.; Hehn, M.; Lacour, D.; Montaigne, F.; Canals, B.</AF>
   <BF></BF>
   <CA></CA>
   <TI>Nonuniversality of artificial frustrated spin systems</TI>
   <SO>PHYSICAL REVIEW B</SO>
   <SE></SE>
   <BS></BS>
   <LA>English</LA>
   <DT>Article</DT>
   <CT></CT>
   <CY></CY>
   <CL></CL>
   <SP></SP>
   <HO></HO>
   <DE></DE>
   <ID>ICE; ARRAYS</ID>
   <AB>Magnetic frustration effects in artificial kagome arrays of nanomagnets with out-of-plane magnetization are investigated using magnetic force microscopy and Monte Carlo simulations. Experimental and theoretical results are compared to those found for the artificial kagome spin ice in which the nanomagnets have in-plane magnetization. In contrast with what has been recently reported, we demonstrate that long-range (i.e., beyond nearest-neighbor) dipolar interactions between the nanomagnets cannot be neglected when describing the magnetic configurations observed after demagnetizing the arrays using a field protocol. As a consequence, there are clear limits to any universality in the behavior of these two artificial frustrated spin systems. We provide arguments to explain why these two systems show striking similarities at first sight in the development of pairwise spin correlations.</AB>
   <C1>[Chioar, I. A.; Rougemaille, N.; Grimm, A.; Fruchart, O.; Wagner, E.; Canals, B.] CNRS, Inst NEEL, F-38042 Grenoble, France; [Chioar, I. A.; Rougemaille, N.; Grimm, A.; Fruchart, O.; Wagner, E.; Canals, B.] Univ Grenoble Alpes, Inst NEEL, F-38042 Grenoble, France; [Hehn, M.; Lacour, D.; Montaigne, F.] Univ Lorraine, Inst Jean Lamour, CNRS, F-54506 Vandoeuvre Les Nancy, France</C1>
   <RP>Chioar, IA (reprint author), CNRS, Inst NEEL, F-38042 Grenoble, France.</RP>
   <EM></EM>
   <RI></RI>
   <OI></OI>
   <FU>Region Lorraine; Agence National de la Recherche [ANR12-BS04-009]; Laboratoire d'excellence LANEF Grenoble</FU>
   <FX>This work was partially supported by the Region Lorraine and the Agence National de la Recherche through Project ANR12-BS04-009 "Frustrated." I. A. Chioar acknowledges financial support from the Laboratoire d'excellence LANEF Grenoble. The authors also thank S. Le-Denmat for technical help with the AFM/MFM measurements.</FX>
   <CR></CR>
   <NR>31</NR>
   <TC>0</TC>
   <Z9>0</Z9>
   <PU>AMER PHYSICAL SOC</PU>
   <PI>COLLEGE PK</PI>
   <PA>ONE PHYSICS ELLIPSE, COLLEGE PK, MD 20740-3844 USA</PA>
   <SN>1098-0121</SN>
   <EI>1550-235X</EI>
   <BN></BN>
   <J9>PHYS REV B</J9>
   <JI>Phys. Rev. B</JI>
   <PD>AUG 11</PD>
   <PY>2014</PY>
   <VL>90</VL>
   <IS>6</IS>
   <PN></PN>
   <SU></SU>
   <SI></SI>
   <MA></MA>
   <BP></BP>
   <EP></EP>
   <AR>064411</AR>
   <DI>10.1103/PhysRevB.90.064411</DI>
   <D2></D2>
   <PG>6</PG>
   <WC>Physics, Condensed Matter</WC>
   <SC>Physics</SC>
   <GA>AO2NW</GA>
   <UT>WOS:000341162300004</UT>
   <PM></PM>
</bibliography>
