<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<bibliography>
   <PT>J</PT>
   <AU>Rajanikanth, A; Hauet, T; Montaigne, F; Mangin, S; Andrieu, S</AU>
   <BA></BA>
   <BE></BE>
   <GP></GP>
   <AF>Rajanikanth, A.; Hauet, T.; Montaigne, F.; Mangin, S.; Andrieu, S.</AF>
   <BF></BF>
   <CA></CA>
   <TI>Magnetic anisotropy modified by electric field in V/Fe/MgO(001)/Fe epitaxial magnetic tunnel junction</TI>
   <SO>APPLIED PHYSICS LETTERS</SO>
   <SE></SE>
   <BS></BS>
   <LA>English</LA>
   <DT>Article</DT>
   <CT></CT>
   <CY></CY>
   <CL></CL>
   <SP></SP>
   <HO></HO>
   <DE></DE>
   <ID>MEMORY</ID>
   <AB>Single-crystalline V/Fe(0.7 nm)/MgO(1.2nm)/Fe(20 nm) magnetic tunnel junctions are studied to quantify the influence of an electric field on the Fe/MgO interface magnetic anisotropy. The thinnest Fe soft layer has a perpendicular magnetic anisotropy (PMA), whereas the thickest Fe layer acts as sensor for magnetic anisotropy changes. When electrons are added at the PMA Fe/MgO interface (negative voltage), no anisotropy changes are observed. For positive voltage, the anisotropy constant decreases with increasing bias voltage. A huge 1150 fJV(-1) m(-1) anisotropy variation with field is observed and the magnetization is found to turn from out-of-plane to in-plane of the sample with the applied voltage. (C) 2013 AIP Publishing LLC.</AB>
   <C1>[Rajanikanth, A.; Hauet, T.; Montaigne, F.; Mangin, S.; Andrieu, S.] Univ Lorraine, CNRS, UMR 7198, Inst Jean Lamour, F-54506 Vandoeuvre Les Nancy, France</C1>
   <RP>Andrieu, S (reprint author), Univ Lorraine, CNRS, UMR 7198, Inst Jean Lamour, F-54506 Vandoeuvre Les Nancy, France.</RP>
   <EM>stephane.andrieu@univ-lorraine.fr</EM>
   <RI></RI>
   <OI></OI>
   <FU>French Agence Nationale de la Recherche [ANR-2010-BLANC-1006]; Region Lorraine</FU>
   <FX>We would like to thank Eric Fullerton for fruitful discussion, and Robert Tolley for improving the English of this paper. This work was supported by the French Agence Nationale de la Recherche, ELECMADE Project No. ANR-2010-BLANC-1006 and the Region Lorraine.</FX>
   <CR></CR>
   <NR>24</NR>
   <TC>3</TC>
   <Z9>3</Z9>
   <PU>AMER INST PHYSICS</PU>
   <PI>MELVILLE</PI>
   <PA>CIRCULATION & FULFILLMENT DIV, 2 HUNTINGTON QUADRANGLE, STE 1 N O 1, MELVILLE, NY 11747-4501 USA</PA>
   <SN>0003-6951</SN>
   <EI></EI>
   <BN></BN>
   <J9>APPL PHYS LETT</J9>
   <JI>Appl. Phys. Lett.</JI>
   <PD>AUG 5</PD>
   <PY>2013</PY>
   <VL>103</VL>
   <IS>6</IS>
   <PN></PN>
   <SU></SU>
   <SI></SI>
   <MA></MA>
   <BP></BP>
   <EP></EP>
   <AR>062402</AR>
   <DI>10.1063/1.4817268</DI>
   <D2></D2>
   <PG>4</PG>
   <WC>Physics, Applied</WC>
   <SC>Physics</SC>
   <GA>198FT</GA>
   <UT>WOS:000322908300045</UT>
   <PM></PM>
</bibliography>
