<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<bibliography>
   <PT>J</PT>
   <AU>Rougemaille, N; Montaigne, F; Canals, B; Duluard, A; Lacour, D; Hehn, M; Belkhou, R; Fruchart, O; El Moussaoui, S; Bendounan, A; Maccherozzi, F</AU>
   <BA></BA>
   <BE></BE>
   <GP></GP>
   <AF>Rougemaille, N.; Montaigne, F.; Canals, B.; Duluard, A.; Lacour, D.; Hehn, M.; Belkhou, R.; Fruchart, O.; El Moussaoui, S.; Bendounan, A.; Maccherozzi, F.</AF>
   <BF></BF>
   <CA></CA>
   <TI>Artificial Kagome Arrays of Nanomagnets: A Frozen Dipolar Spin Ice</TI>
   <SO>PHYSICAL REVIEW LETTERS</SO>
   <SE></SE>
   <BS></BS>
   <LA>English</LA>
   <DT>Article</DT>
   <CT></CT>
   <CY></CY>
   <CL></CL>
   <SP></SP>
   <HO></HO>
   <DE></DE>
   <ID></ID>
   <AB>Magnetic frustration effects in artificial kagome arrays of nanomagnets are investigated using x-ray photoemission electron microscopy and Monte Carlo simulations. Spin configurations of demagnetized networks reveal unambiguous signatures of long range, dipolar interaction between the nanomagnets. As soon as the system enters the spin ice manifold, the kagome dipolar spin ice model captures the observed physics, while the short range kagome spin ice model fails.</AB>
   <C1>[Rougemaille, N.; Canals, B.; Fruchart, O.] UJF, CNRS, Inst Neel, F-38042 Grenoble 9, France; [Montaigne, F.; Duluard, A.; Lacour, D.; Hehn, M.] Nancy Univ, CNRS, Inst Jean Lamour, F-54506 Vandoeuvre Les Nancy, France; [Belkhou, R.; El Moussaoui, S.; Bendounan, A.; Maccherozzi, F.] Synchrotron SOLEIL, F-91192 Gif Sur Yvette, France; [Belkhou, R.; El Moussaoui, S.; Bendounan, A.; Maccherozzi, F.] Sincrotrone Trieste, ELETTRA, I-34012 Trieste, Italy</C1>
   <RP>Rougemaille, N (reprint author), UJF, CNRS, Inst Neel, BP 166, F-38042 Grenoble 9, France.</RP>
   <EM></EM>
   <RI>El Moussaoui, Souliman/O-1043-2014</RI>
   <OI></OI>
   <FU></FU>
   <FX></FX>
   <CR></CR>
   <NR>17</NR>
   <TC>33</TC>
   <Z9>33</Z9>
   <PU>AMER PHYSICAL SOC</PU>
   <PI>COLLEGE PK</PI>
   <PA>ONE PHYSICS ELLIPSE, COLLEGE PK, MD 20740-3844 USA</PA>
   <SN>0031-9007</SN>
   <EI></EI>
   <BN></BN>
   <J9>PHYS REV LETT</J9>
   <JI>Phys. Rev. Lett.</JI>
   <PD>FEB 4</PD>
   <PY>2011</PY>
   <VL>106</VL>
   <IS>5</IS>
   <PN></PN>
   <SU></SU>
   <SI></SI>
   <MA></MA>
   <BP></BP>
   <EP></EP>
   <AR>057209</AR>
   <DI>10.1103/PhysRevLett.106.057209</DI>
   <D2></D2>
   <PG>4</PG>
   <WC>Physics, Multidisciplinary</WC>
   <SC>Physics</SC>
   <GA>716PR</GA>
   <UT>WOS:000286986400013</UT>
   <PM>21405433</PM>
</bibliography>
