<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<bibliography>
   <PT>J</PT>
   <AU>Melchior, P; Rollinger, M; Thielen, P; Alebrand, S; Bierbrauer, U; Schneider, C; Gottwald, M; Hehn, M; Mangin, S; Cinchetti, M; Aeschlimann, M</AU>
   <BA></BA>
   <BE></BE>
   <GP></GP>
   <AF>Melchior, Pascal; Rollinger, Markus; Thielen, Philip; Alebrand, Sabine; Bierbrauer, Ute; Schneider, Christian; Gottwald, Matthias; Hehn, Michel; Mangin, Stephane; Cinchetti, Mirko; Aeschlimann, Martin</AF>
   <BF></BF>
   <CA></CA>
   <TI>Energy-resolved magnetic domain imaging in TbCo alloys by valence band photoemission magnetic circular dichroism</TI>
   <SO>PHYSICAL REVIEW B</SO>
   <SE></SE>
   <BS></BS>
   <LA>English</LA>
   <DT>Article</DT>
   <CT></CT>
   <CY></CY>
   <CL></CL>
   <SP></SP>
   <HO></HO>
   <DE></DE>
   <ID>RARE-EARTH-METALS; ELECTRONIC-STRUCTURE; MICROSCOPY; DYNAMICS; FILMS</ID>
   <AB>We report magnetic domain imaging of a terbium cobalt (TbCo) alloy thin film with a high perpendicular magnetic anisotropy in one- and two-photon photoemission electron microscopy (PEEM). Both photoemission processes deliver a clear magnetic circular dichroism (MCD) whose strength is strongly energy dependent. Comparing the energy dependence of the MCD signal in one- and two-photon photoemission, we conclude that the magnetic contrast is mainly an initial state effect. Our results ultimately show that MCD contrast can be obtained in PEEM in valence band photoemission from a material supporting all-optical magnetization switching. This opens the way for the investigation of the all-optical switching process with simultaneous ultrahigh temporal and spatial resolution.</AB>
   <C1>[Melchior, Pascal; Rollinger, Markus; Thielen, Philip; Alebrand, Sabine; Bierbrauer, Ute; Schneider, Christian; Cinchetti, Mirko; Aeschlimann, Martin] Univ Kaiserslautern, Dept Phys, D-67663 Kaiserslautern, Germany; [Melchior, Pascal; Rollinger, Markus; Thielen, Philip; Alebrand, Sabine; Bierbrauer, Ute; Schneider, Christian; Cinchetti, Mirko; Aeschlimann, Martin] Univ Kaiserslautern, Res Ctr OPTIMAS, D-67663 Kaiserslautern, Germany; [Thielen, Philip] Grad Sch Excellence Mat Sci Mainz, D-67663 Kaiserslautern, Germany; [Gottwald, Matthias; Mangin, Stephane] Univ Calif San Diego, Ctr Magnet Recording Res, La Jolla, CA 92093 USA; [Hehn, Michel; Mangin, Stephane] Univ Lorraine, Inst Jean Lamour, UMR CNRS 7198, F-54505 Vandoeuvre Les Nancy, France</C1>
   <RP>Melchior, P (reprint author), Univ Kaiserslautern, Dept Phys, Erwin Schroedinger Str 46, D-67663 Kaiserslautern, Germany.</RP>
   <EM>melchior@physik.uni-kl.de</EM>
   <RI>Aeschlimann, Martin/D-7141-2011; Cinchetti, Mirko/F-9769-2010</RI>
   <OI>Cinchetti, Mirko/0000-0003-0735-8921</OI>
   <FU>Excellence Initiative MAINZ Graduate School for Materials Science in Mainz [DFG/GSC 266]; region Lorraine; European FP7 Marie Curie grant [OP2M]</FU>
   <FX>We acknowledge fruitful discussions with Eric E. Fullerton and the valuable support of Andreas Oelsner (Surface Concept GmbH) for the ToF-DLD. Additionally, we thankfully acknowledge the financial support by the Excellence Initiative (DFG/GSC 266) MAINZ Graduate School for Materials Science in Mainz (to P.T.), the region Lorraine, and the European FP7 Marie Curie grant OP2M.</FX>
   <CR></CR>
   <NR>30</NR>
   <TC>2</TC>
   <Z9>2</Z9>
   <PU>AMER PHYSICAL SOC</PU>
   <PI>COLLEGE PK</PI>
   <PA>ONE PHYSICS ELLIPSE, COLLEGE PK, MD 20740-3844 USA</PA>
   <SN>1098-0121</SN>
   <EI></EI>
   <BN></BN>
   <J9>PHYS REV B</J9>
   <JI>Phys. Rev. B</JI>
   <PD>SEP 18</PD>
   <PY>2013</PY>
   <VL>88</VL>
   <IS>10</IS>
   <PN></PN>
   <SU></SU>
   <SI></SI>
   <MA></MA>
   <BP></BP>
   <EP></EP>
   <AR>104415</AR>
   <DI>10.1103/PhysRevB.88.104415</DI>
   <D2></D2>
   <PG>6</PG>
   <WC>Physics, Condensed Matter</WC>
   <SC>Physics</SC>
   <GA>219VM</GA>
   <UT>WOS:000324539200003</UT>
   <PM></PM>
</bibliography>
