<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<bibliography>
   <PT>J</PT>
   <AU>Bonell, F; Hauet, T; Andrieu, S; Bertran, F; Le Fevre, P; Calmels, L; Tejeda, A; Montaigne, F; Warot-Fonrose, B; Belhadji, B; Nicolaou, A; Taleb-Ibrahimi, A</AU>
   <BA></BA>
   <BE></BE>
   <GP></GP>
   <AF>Bonell, F.; Hauet, T.; Andrieu, S.; Bertran, F.; Le Fevre, P.; Calmels, L.; Tejeda, A.; Montaigne, F.; Warot-Fonrose, B.; Belhadji, B.; Nicolaou, A.; Taleb-Ibrahimi, A.</AF>
   <BF></BF>
   <CA></CA>
   <TI>Spin-Polarized Electron Tunneling in bcc FeCo/MgO/FeCo(001) Magnetic Tunnel Junctions</TI>
   <SO>PHYSICAL REVIEW LETTERS</SO>
   <SE></SE>
   <BS></BS>
   <LA>English</LA>
   <DT>Article</DT>
   <CT></CT>
   <CY></CY>
   <CL></CL>
   <SP></SP>
   <HO></HO>
   <DE></DE>
   <ID>ROOM-TEMPERATURE; LARGE MAGNETORESISTANCE; TRANSFER-TORQUE; CO/MGO/CO</ID>
   <AB>In combining spin-and symmetry-resolved photoemission, magnetotransport measurements and ab initio calculations we detangled the electronic states involved in the electronic transport in Fe1-xCox(001)/MgO/Fe1-xCox(001) magnetic tunnel junctions. Contrary to previous theoretical predictions, we observe a large reduction in TMR (from 530 to 200% at 20 K) for Co content above 25 atomic % as well as anomalies in the conductance curves. We demonstrate that these unexpected behaviors originate from a minority spin state with Delta(1) symmetry that exists below the Fermi level for high Co concentration. Using angle-resolved photoemission, this state is shown to be a two-dimensional state that occurs at both Fe1-xCox(001) free surface, and more importantly at the interface with MgO. The combination of this interface state with the peculiar density of empty states due to chemical disorder allows us to describe in details the complex conduction behavior in this system.</AB>
   <C1>[Bonell, F.; Hauet, T.; Andrieu, S.; Tejeda, A.; Montaigne, F.] Nancy Univ CNRS, Inst Jean Lamour, F-54506 Vandoeuvre Les Nancy, France; [Bertran, F.; Le Fevre, P.; Tejeda, A.] Synchrotron SOLEIL CNRS, F-91192 Gif Sur Yvette, France; [Calmels, L.; Warot-Fonrose, B.; Belhadji, B.] Univ Toulouse, CEMES CNRS, F-31055 Toulouse, France</C1>
   <RP>Andrieu, S (reprint author), Nancy Univ CNRS, Inst Jean Lamour, Bd Aiguillettes,BP239, F-54506 Vandoeuvre Les Nancy, France.</RP>
   <EM></EM>
   <RI>BERTRAN, Francois/B-7515-2008; Tejeda, Antonio/C-4711-2014</RI>
   <OI>BERTRAN, Francois/0000-0002-2416-0514; Tejeda, Antonio/0000-0003-0125-4603</OI>
   <FU></FU>
   <FX></FX>
   <CR></CR>
   <NR>30</NR>
   <TC>17</TC>
   <Z9>17</Z9>
   <PU>AMER PHYSICAL SOC</PU>
   <PI>COLLEGE PK</PI>
   <PA>ONE PHYSICS ELLIPSE, COLLEGE PK, MD 20740-3844 USA</PA>
   <SN>0031-9007</SN>
   <EI></EI>
   <BN></BN>
   <J9>PHYS REV LETT</J9>
   <JI>Phys. Rev. Lett.</JI>
   <PD>APR 25</PD>
   <PY>2012</PY>
   <VL>108</VL>
   <IS>17</IS>
   <PN></PN>
   <SU></SU>
   <SI></SI>
   <MA></MA>
   <BP></BP>
   <EP></EP>
   <AR>176602</AR>
   <DI>10.1103/PhysRevLett.108.176602</DI>
   <D2></D2>
   <PG>5</PG>
   <WC>Physics, Multidisciplinary</WC>
   <SC>Physics</SC>
   <GA>931DT</GA>
   <UT>WOS:000303196000005</UT>
   <PM>22680889</PM>
</bibliography>
