<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<bibliography>
   <PT>J</PT>
   <AU>Zhang, H; Lin, WW; Mangin, S; Zhang, ZZ; Liu, YW</AU>
   <BA></BA>
   <BE></BE>
   <GP></GP>
   <AF>Zhang, Hong; Lin, Weiwei; Mangin, Stephane; Zhang, Zongzhi; Liu, Yaowen</AF>
   <BF></BF>
   <CA></CA>
   <TI>Signature of magnetization dynamics in spin-transfer-driven nanopillars with tilted easy axis</TI>
   <SO>APPLIED PHYSICS LETTERS</SO>
   <SE></SE>
   <BS></BS>
   <LA>English</LA>
   <DT>Article</DT>
   <CT></CT>
   <CY></CY>
   <CL></CL>
   <SP></SP>
   <HO></HO>
   <DE></DE>
   <ID>PERPENDICULAR-ANISOTROPY; TORQUE OSCILLATOR; MULTILAYERS; POLARIZER; REVERSAL; DEVICES; LAYER</ID>
   <AB>Special spin-transfer-driven magnetic behaviors can take place in a spin valve nanopillar with perpendicular anisotropy due to reduced symmetry of easy axis. Micromagnetic simulation demonstrates a dip in the average magnetization curve, which corresponds to the experimentally observed undulation of dc resistance. The dip is a signature of spin-transfer-driven reversable magnetic process with slightly tilted easy axis in the free layer. This featured magnetization dynamics includes non-uniform magnetization precession and multi-mode propagating spin waves, which are attributed to the competition among tilted magnetic anisotropy, magnetic field, and spin transfer torque. (C) 2013 American Institute of Physics. [http://dx.doi.org/10.1063/1.4775675]</AB>
   <C1>[Zhang, Hong; Liu, Yaowen] Tongji Univ, Shanghai Key Lab Special Artificial Microstruct M, Dept Phys, Shanghai 200092, Peoples R China; [Zhang, Hong] Shandong Agr Univ, Informat Sci & Engn Sch, Tai An 271018, Shandong, Peoples R China; [Lin, Weiwei; Mangin, Stephane] Nancy Univ, Inst Jean Lamour, F-54506 Vandoeuvre Les Nancy, France; [Zhang, Zongzhi] Fudan Univ, Dept Opt Sci & Engn, Shanghai 200433, Peoples R China</C1>
   <RP>Liu, YW (reprint author), Tongji Univ, Shanghai Key Lab Special Artificial Microstruct M, Dept Phys, Shanghai 200092, Peoples R China.</RP>
   <EM>yaowen@tongji.edu.cn</EM>
   <RI>Lin, Weiwei/D-4870-2009; Liu, Yaowen /H-6337-2011</RI>
   <OI>Lin, Weiwei/0000-0002-8567-0323; </OI>
   <FU>NSFC [51171047, 10974142, 11074046, 11274241, 51222103]; New Century Educational Talents Plan of the Chinese Education Ministry [NCET-10-0603]; Fundamental Research Funds for the Central Universities; National Basic Research Program of China [2009CB929201]</FU>
   <FX>The authors greatly acknowledge the Hitachi GST for sample preparation. This work was supported by the NSFC (Grant Nos. 51171047, 10974142, 11074046 and 11274241, and 51222103). Y. Liu would like to thank the New Century Educational Talents Plan of the Chinese Education Ministry (NCET-10-0603) and the Fundamental Research Funds for the Central Universities. S. Mangin would like to thank ANR project FRIEND. Z. Zhang thanks the support from the National Basic Research Program of China (2009CB929201).</FX>
   <CR></CR>
   <NR>25</NR>
   <TC>1</TC>
   <Z9>1</Z9>
   <PU>AMER INST PHYSICS</PU>
   <PI>MELVILLE</PI>
   <PA>CIRCULATION & FULFILLMENT DIV, 2 HUNTINGTON QUADRANGLE, STE 1 N O 1, MELVILLE, NY 11747-4501 USA</PA>
   <SN>0003-6951</SN>
   <EI></EI>
   <BN></BN>
   <J9>APPL PHYS LETT</J9>
   <JI>Appl. Phys. Lett.</JI>
   <PD>JAN 7</PD>
   <PY>2013</PY>
   <VL>102</VL>
   <IS>1</IS>
   <PN></PN>
   <SU></SU>
   <SI></SI>
   <MA></MA>
   <BP></BP>
   <EP></EP>
   <AR>012411</AR>
   <DI>10.1063/1.4775675</DI>
   <D2></D2>
   <PG>5</PG>
   <WC>Physics, Applied</WC>
   <SC>Physics</SC>
   <GA>072CQ</GA>
   <UT>WOS:000313646500084</UT>
   <PM></PM>
</bibliography>
