<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<bibliography>
   <PT>J</PT>
   <AU>Briones, J; Toro, P; Encinas, A; Caballero, L; Denardin, JC; Melo, F; Cerda, E; Robert, S; Lacour, D; Montaigne, F</AU>
   <BA></BA>
   <BE></BE>
   <GP></GP>
   <AF>Briones, J.; Toro, P.; Encinas, A.; Caballero, L.; Denardin, J. C.; Melo, F.; Cerda, E.; Robert, S.; Lacour, D.; Montaigne, F.</AF>
   <BF></BF>
   <CA></CA>
   <TI>Large area patterned magnetic films by depositing cobalt layers on nano-wrinkled polydimethylsiloxane templates</TI>
   <SO>APPLIED PHYSICS LETTERS</SO>
   <SE></SE>
   <BS></BS>
   <LA>English</LA>
   <DT>Article</DT>
   <CT></CT>
   <CY></CY>
   <CL></CL>
   <SP></SP>
   <HO></HO>
   <DE></DE>
   <ID>THIN-FILMS; ELASTOMERIC POLYMER; SELF-ORGANIZATION; ANODIC ALUMINA; SURFACES; ARRAYS; ELECTRODEPOSITION; BIOCOMPATIBILITY; IRRADIATION; ELECTRONICS</ID>
   <AB>We report on a method to fabricate laterally modulated Co films using the artificially induced nano-wrinkled surface of a polydimethylsiloxane polymeric film as template. Large area patterning of self-organized parallel wrinkles is formed displaying a submicrometer wavelength. The subsequent deposition of a Co layer on this wavy surface yields a uniaxial magnetic anisotropy imposed by the wrinkles' morphology. Measurement of the remanent magnetization and coercive field as a function of the field angle confirms the uniaxial nature of the anisotropy and reveals a reversal mechanism more complex than pure coherent rotation. The magnetostatic origin of the anisotropy is analyzed. (C) 2013 AIP Publishing LLC.</AB>
   <C1>[Briones, J.; Toro, P.; Caballero, L.; Denardin, J. C.; Melo, F.; Cerda, E.] Univ Santiago Chile USACH, Dept Fis, Santiago 9170124, Chile; [Briones, J.; Toro, P.; Denardin, J. C.] CEDENNA, Ctr Dev Nanosci & Nanotechnol, Santiago 9170124, Chile; [Encinas, A.] Univ Autonoma San Luis Potosi, Inst Fis, San Luis Potosi 78290, SLP, Mexico; [Robert, S.; Lacour, D.; Montaigne, F.] Univ Lorraine, Inst Jean Lamour, CNRS, F-54506 Vandoeuvre Les Nancy, France</C1>
   <RP>Briones, J (reprint author), Univ Santiago Chile USACH, Dept Fis, Santiago 9170124, Chile.</RP>
   <EM>joel.briones@usach.cl</EM>
   <RI>Encinas, Armando/O-1188-2013; Melo, Francisco/M-3923-2014</RI>
   <OI>Encinas, Armando/0000-0003-4965-282X; </OI>
   <FU>FONDECYT [3120059, 1110252]; USAFOSR [FA9550-11-1-0347]; Fondo de Innovacion para la Competitividad-MINECON [ICM P10-061-F]; Financiamiento Basal para Centros Cientificos y Tecnologicos de Excelencia [FB0807]; CONACYT [CB-105568]</FU>
   <FX>Support from FONDECYT under projects 3120059, 1110252; USAFOSR Award No. FA9550-11-1-0347; Grant ICM P10-061-F by Fondo de Innovacion para la Competitividad-MINECON; Financiamiento Basal para Centros Cientificos y Tecnologicos de Excelencia under project FB0807; and CONACYT CB-105568 are gratefully acknowledged.</FX>
   <CR></CR>
   <NR>47</NR>
   <TC>0</TC>
   <Z9>0</Z9>
   <PU>AMER INST PHYSICS</PU>
   <PI>MELVILLE</PI>
   <PA>CIRCULATION & FULFILLMENT DIV, 2 HUNTINGTON QUADRANGLE, STE 1 N O 1, MELVILLE, NY 11747-4501 USA</PA>
   <SN>0003-6951</SN>
   <EI></EI>
   <BN></BN>
   <J9>APPL PHYS LETT</J9>
   <JI>Appl. Phys. Lett.</JI>
   <PD>AUG 12</PD>
   <PY>2013</PY>
   <VL>103</VL>
   <IS>7</IS>
   <PN></PN>
   <SU></SU>
   <SI></SI>
   <MA></MA>
   <BP></BP>
   <EP></EP>
   <AR>072404</AR>
   <DI>10.1063/1.4818677</DI>
   <D2></D2>
   <PG>5</PG>
   <WC>Physics, Applied</WC>
   <SC>Physics</SC>
   <GA>209OS</GA>
   <UT>WOS:000323769000050</UT>
   <PM></PM>
</bibliography>
