<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<bibliography>
   <PT>J</PT>
   <AU>Alebrand, S; Gottwald, M; Hehn, M; Steil, D; Cinchetti, M; Lacour, D; Fullerton, EE; Aeschlimann, M; Mangin, S</AU>
   <BA></BA>
   <BE></BE>
   <GP></GP>
   <AF>Alebrand, Sabine; Gottwald, Matthias; Hehn, Michel; Steil, Daniel; Cinchetti, Mirko; Lacour, Daniel; Fullerton, Eric E.; Aeschlimann, Martin; Mangin, Stephane</AF>
   <BF></BF>
   <CA></CA>
   <TI>Light-induced magnetization reversal of high-anisotropy TbCo alloy films</TI>
   <SO>APPLIED PHYSICS LETTERS</SO>
   <SE></SE>
   <BS></BS>
   <LA>English</LA>
   <DT>Article</DT>
   <CT></CT>
   <CY></CY>
   <CL></CL>
   <SP></SP>
   <HO></HO>
   <DE></DE>
   <ID></ID>
   <AB>Magnetization reversal using circularly polarized light provides a way to control magnetization without any external magnetic field and has the potential to revolutionize magnetic data storage. However, in order to reach ultra-high density data storage, high anisotropy media providing thermal stability are needed. Here, we evidence all-optical magnetization switching for different TbxCo1-x ferrimagnetic alloy compositions using fs- and ps-laser pulses and demonstrate all-optical switching for films with anisotropy fields reaching 6 T corresponding to anisotropy constants of 3 x 10(6) ergs/cm(3). Optical magnetization switching is observed only for alloy compositions where the compensation temperature can be reached through sample heating. (C) 2012 American Institute of Physics. [http://dx.doi.org/10.1063/1.4759109]</AB>
   <C1>[Gottwald, Matthias; Hehn, Michel; Lacour, Daniel; Mangin, Stephane] Univ Lorraine, UMR CNRS 7198, Inst Jean Lamour, F-54505 Vandoeuvre Les Nancy, France; [Alebrand, Sabine; Steil, Daniel; Cinchetti, Mirko; Aeschlimann, Martin] Univ Kaiserslautern, Dept Phys, D-67663 Kaiserslautern, Germany; [Alebrand, Sabine; Steil, Daniel; Cinchetti, Mirko; Aeschlimann, Martin] Univ Kaiserslautern, Res Ctr OPTIMAS, D-67663 Kaiserslautern, Germany; [Gottwald, Matthias; Fullerton, Eric E.] Univ Calif San Diego, Ctr Magnet Recording Res, San Diego, CA 92093 USA</C1>
   <RP>Mangin, S (reprint author), Univ Lorraine, UMR CNRS 7198, Inst Jean Lamour, F-54505 Vandoeuvre Les Nancy, France.</RP>
   <EM>stephane.mangin@ijl.nancy-universite.fr</EM>
   <RI>Cinchetti, Mirko/F-9769-2010; Fullerton, Eric/H-8445-2013; Aeschlimann, Martin/D-7141-2011</RI>
   <OI>Cinchetti, Mirko/0000-0003-0735-8921; Fullerton, Eric/0000-0002-4725-9509; </OI>
   <FU>Partner University Fund "Novel Magnetic Materials for Spin Torque Physics and Devices"; Region Lorraine; Institut Universitaire de France; Grosse/Grande Region;  [ANR-10-BLAN-1005 "Friends"];  [ANR-09-Blan-076 "SpinPress"]</FU>
   <FX>We acknowledge the Photonik-Zentrum Kaiserslautern e.V., especially Dr. J. L'huillier for access to and T. Herrmann and M. Stolze for technical support with the ps laser system. Further, we thank A. Hassdenteufel for establishing the switching experiment. We thank Region Lorraine, Institut Universitaire de France, Grosse/Grande Region, for their financial support. We thank The CC-Magnetisme from IJL and especially T. Hauet and S. Suire for their support with magnetic measurements. This work was also supported by The Partner University Fund "Novel Magnetic Materials for Spin Torque Physics and Devices" and the ANR-10-BLAN-1005 "Friends" and ANR-09-Blan-076 "SpinPress."</FX>
   <CR></CR>
   <NR>18</NR>
   <TC>17</TC>
   <Z9>17</Z9>
   <PU>AMER INST PHYSICS</PU>
   <PI>MELVILLE</PI>
   <PA>CIRCULATION & FULFILLMENT DIV, 2 HUNTINGTON QUADRANGLE, STE 1 N O 1, MELVILLE, NY 11747-4501 USA</PA>
   <SN>0003-6951</SN>
   <EI></EI>
   <BN></BN>
   <J9>APPL PHYS LETT</J9>
   <JI>Appl. Phys. Lett.</JI>
   <PD>OCT 15</PD>
   <PY>2012</PY>
   <VL>101</VL>
   <IS>16</IS>
   <PN></PN>
   <SU></SU>
   <SI></SI>
   <MA></MA>
   <BP></BP>
   <EP></EP>
   <AR>162408</AR>
   <DI>10.1063/1.4759109</DI>
   <D2></D2>
   <PG>4</PG>
   <WC>Physics, Applied</WC>
   <SC>Physics</SC>
   <GA>031UZ</GA>
   <UT>WOS:000310669300047</UT>
   <PM></PM>
</bibliography>
