<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<bibliography>
   <PT>J</PT>
   <AU>Lu, Y; Lacour, D; Lengaigne, G; Le Gall, S; Suire, S; Montaigne, F; Hehn, M</AU>
   <BA></BA>
   <BE></BE>
   <GP></GP>
   <AF>Lu, Y.; Lacour, D.; Lengaigne, G.; Le Gall, S.; Suire, S.; Montaigne, F.; Hehn, M.</AF>
   <BF></BF>
   <CA></CA>
   <TI>Interfacial trapping for hot electron injection in silicon</TI>
   <SO>APPLIED PHYSICS LETTERS</SO>
   <SE></SE>
   <BS></BS>
   <LA>English</LA>
   <DT>Article</DT>
   <CT></CT>
   <CY></CY>
   <CL></CL>
   <SP></SP>
   <HO></HO>
   <DE></DE>
   <ID>SPIN-VALVE TRANSISTOR</ID>
   <AB>We have evidenced a new interfacial trapping phenomenon for hot electron injection in silicon by studying magnetic tunnel transistors (MTTs) with a MgO tunneling barrier emitter and a Cu/Si Shottky barrier collector. Transport measurements on hot electrons indicate that an interfacial charge trapping and a backscattering-induced collector current limitation take place with the MTT spin-valve base both in parallel and antiparallel states when the temperature is lower than 25 K, which results in a rapid decrease of the magnetocurrent ratio from similar to 2000% at 25K to 800% at 17 K. The binding energy of the trapped electron is estimated to be about 1.7 meV, which is also found to increase with the magnetic field. A simple analytic model considering the interfacial electron trapping and releasing is proposed to explain the experimental results. (C) 2013 AIP Publishing LLC.</AB>
   <C1>[Lu, Y.; Lacour, D.; Lengaigne, G.; Le Gall, S.; Suire, S.; Montaigne, F.; Hehn, M.] Nancy Univ, CNRS, UMR 7198, Inst Jean Lamour, F-54506 Vandoeuvre Les Nancy, France</C1>
   <RP>Lu, Y (reprint author), Nancy Univ, CNRS, UMR 7198, Inst Jean Lamour, BP 239, F-54506 Vandoeuvre Les Nancy, France.</RP>
   <EM>yuan.lu@univ-lorraine.fr</EM>
   <RI>Lu, Yuan/M-9239-2014</RI>
   <OI>Lu, Yuan/0000-0003-3337-8205</OI>
   <FU>French ANR SpinPress project; region Lorraine</FU>
   <FX>We thank Professor M. W. Wu for fruitful discussion. This work was supported by French ANR SpinPress project and region Lorraine.</FX>
   <CR></CR>
   <NR>16</NR>
   <TC>3</TC>
   <Z9>3</Z9>
   <PU>AMER INST PHYSICS</PU>
   <PI>MELVILLE</PI>
   <PA>CIRCULATION & FULFILLMENT DIV, 2 HUNTINGTON QUADRANGLE, STE 1 N O 1, MELVILLE, NY 11747-4501 USA</PA>
   <SN>0003-6951</SN>
   <EI></EI>
   <BN></BN>
   <J9>APPL PHYS LETT</J9>
   <JI>Appl. Phys. Lett.</JI>
   <PD>JUL 8</PD>
   <PY>2013</PY>
   <VL>103</VL>
   <IS>2</IS>
   <PN></PN>
   <SU></SU>
   <SI></SI>
   <MA></MA>
   <BP></BP>
   <EP></EP>
   <AR>022407</AR>
   <DI>10.1063/1.4813015</DI>
   <D2></D2>
   <PG>4</PG>
   <WC>Physics, Applied</WC>
   <SC>Physics</SC>
   <GA>182RH</GA>
   <UT>WOS:000321761000049</UT>
   <PM></PM>
</bibliography>
