<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<bibliography>
   <PT>J</PT>
   <AU>Montaigne, F; Lacour, D; Chioar, IA; Rougemaille, N; Louis, D; Mc Murtry, S; Riahi, H; Burgos, BS; Mentes, TO; Locatelli, A; Canals, B; Hehn, M</AU>
   <BA></BA>
   <BE></BE>
   <GP></GP>
   <AF>Montaigne, F.; Lacour, D.; Chioar, I. A.; Rougemaille, N.; Louis, D.; Mc Murtry, S.; Riahi, H.; Burgos, B. Santos; Mentes, T. O.; Locatelli, A.; Canals, B.; Hehn, M.</AF>
   <BF></BF>
   <CA></CA>
   <TI>Size distribution of magnetic charge domains in thermally activated but out-of-equilibrium artificial spin ice</TI>
   <SO>SCIENTIFIC REPORTS</SO>
   <SE></SE>
   <BS></BS>
   <LA>English</LA>
   <DT>Article</DT>
   <CT></CT>
   <CY></CY>
   <CL></CL>
   <SP></SP>
   <HO></HO>
   <DE></DE>
   <ID></ID>
   <AB>A crystal of emerging magnetic charges is expected in the phase diagram of the dipolar kagome spin ice. An observation of charge crystallites in thermally demagnetized artificial spin ice arrays has been recently reported by S. Zhang and coworkers(1) and explained through the thermodynamics of the system as it approaches a charge-ordered state. Following a similar approach, we have generated a partial order of magnetic charges in an artificial kagome spin ice lattice made out of ferrimagnetic material having a Curie temperature of 475 K. A statistical study of the size of the charge domains reveals an unconventional sawtooth distribution. This distribution is in disagreement with the predictions of the thermodynamic model and is shown to be a signature of the kinetic process governing the remagnetization.</AB>
   <C1>[Montaigne, F.; Lacour, D.; Louis, D.; Mc Murtry, S.; Riahi, H.; Hehn, M.] Univ Lorraine, Inst Jean Lamour, F-54506 Vandoeuvre Les Nancy, France; [Montaigne, F.; Lacour, D.; Louis, D.; Mc Murtry, S.; Riahi, H.; Hehn, M.] CNRS, F-54506 Vandoeuvre Les Nancy, France; [Chioar, I. A.; Rougemaille, N.; Canals, B.] CNRS, Inst NEEL, F-38042 Grenoble, France; [Chioar, I. A.; Rougemaille, N.; Canals, B.] Univ Grenoble Alpes, Inst NEEL, F-38042 Grenoble, France; [Burgos, B. Santos; Mentes, T. O.; Locatelli, A.] Elettra Sincrotrone Trieste SCpA SS, I-34149 Trieste, Italy</C1>
   <RP>Montaigne, F (reprint author), Univ Lorraine, Inst Jean Lamour, F-54506 Vandoeuvre Les Nancy, France.</RP>
   <EM>francois.montaigne@univ-lorraine.fr</EM>
   <RI></RI>
   <OI></OI>
   <FU>French ANR FRUSTRATED Project [ANR-12-BS04-0009]; la region Lorraine; European Union FEDER funds; Laboratoire d'Excellence LANEF Grenoble</FU>
   <FX>French ANR FRUSTRATED Project (ANR-12-BS04-0009), la region Lorraine and European Union FEDER funds are acknowledged for support. I.A Chioar thanks the Laboratoire d'Excellence LANEF Grenoble for financial support.</FX>
   <CR></CR>
   <NR>13</NR>
   <TC>1</TC>
   <Z9>1</Z9>
   <PU>NATURE PUBLISHING GROUP</PU>
   <PI>LONDON</PI>
   <PA>MACMILLAN BUILDING, 4 CRINAN ST, LONDON N1 9XW, ENGLAND</PA>
   <SN>2045-2322</SN>
   <EI></EI>
   <BN></BN>
   <J9>SCI REP-UK</J9>
   <JI>Sci Rep</JI>
   <PD>JUL 16</PD>
   <PY>2014</PY>
   <VL>4</VL>
   <IS></IS>
   <PN></PN>
   <SU></SU>
   <SI></SI>
   <MA></MA>
   <BP></BP>
   <EP></EP>
   <AR>5702</AR>
   <DI>10.1038/srep05702</DI>
   <D2></D2>
   <PG>5</PG>
   <WC>Multidisciplinary Sciences</WC>
   <SC>Science & Technology - Other Topics</SC>
   <GA>AL2YG</GA>
   <UT>WOS:000338991000007</UT>
   <PM>25029620</PM>
</bibliography>
