<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<bibliography>
   <PT>J</PT>
   <AU>Piraux, L; Antohe, VA; Araujo, FA; Srivastava, SK; Hehn, M; Lacour, D; Mangin, S; Hauet, T</AU>
   <BA></BA>
   <BE></BE>
   <GP></GP>
   <AF>Piraux, L.; Antohe, V. A.; Araujo, F. Abreu; Srivastava, S. K.; Hehn, M.; Lacour, D.; Mangin, S.; Hauet, T.</AF>
   <BF></BF>
   <CA></CA>
   <TI>Periodic arrays of magnetic nanostructures by depositing Co/Pt multilayers on the barrier layer of ordered anodic alumina templates</TI>
   <SO>APPLIED PHYSICS LETTERS</SO>
   <SE></SE>
   <BS></BS>
   <LA>English</LA>
   <DT>Article</DT>
   <CT></CT>
   <CY></CY>
   <CL></CL>
   <SP></SP>
   <HO></HO>
   <DE>alumina; cobalt; magnetic multilayers; nanomagnetics; platinum; self-assembly</DE>
   <ID>FABRICATION; NANOWIRES; NANOPORES; FILMS</ID>
   <AB>We developed a method to fabricate ordered Co/Pt multilayer nanodot arrays using the barrier layer of anodic alumina templates as two-dimensional curved substrates. Large area patterning of self-assembled alumina nanobumps are formed with hexagonally close-packed order. The subsequent deposition of Co/Pt multilayers on this bumpy surface leads to an ordered array of single-domain nanocaps magnetized perpendicularly to the sample surface. Measurement of reversal field as a function of field angle and images of demagnetized state, composed with monobump-wide stripe domains, confirm the weakness of exchange coupling between bits. (C) 2012 American Institute of Physics. [http://dx.doi.org/10.1063/1.4731640]</AB>
   <C1>[Piraux, L.; Antohe, V. A.; Araujo, F. Abreu; Srivastava, S. K.] Catholic Univ Louvain, Inst Condensed Matter & Nanosci, B-1348 Louvain, Belgium; [Hehn, M.; Lacour, D.; Mangin, S.; Hauet, T.] Nancy Univ, Inst Jean Lamour, UMR CNRS 7198, F-54506 Vandoeuvre Les Nancy, France</C1>
   <RP>Piraux, L (reprint author), Catholic Univ Louvain, Inst Condensed Matter & Nanosci, Pl Croix Sud 1, B-1348 Louvain, Belgium.</RP>
   <EM>luc.piraux@uclouvain.be</EM>
   <RI>Abreu Araujo, Flavio/K-4532-2014</RI>
   <OI>Abreu Araujo, Flavio/0000-0001-7157-3197</OI>
   <FU>French Community of Belgium via Concerted Research Action ARC NANHYMO [07/12-003];  [ANR-09-BLAN-076]</FU>
   <FX>This work was partly supported by the French Community of Belgium for funding via the Concerted Research Action ARC NANHYMO (Convention 07/12-003). F. A. A. is a Research Fellow of the National Fund for Training in Research in Industry and Agriculture (FRIA), Belgium. This work was also supported by the ANR-09-BLAN-076, "SpinPress."</FX>
   <CR></CR>
   <NR>28</NR>
   <TC>2</TC>
   <Z9>2</Z9>
   <PU>AMER INST PHYSICS</PU>
   <PI>MELVILLE</PI>
   <PA>CIRCULATION & FULFILLMENT DIV, 2 HUNTINGTON QUADRANGLE, STE 1 N O 1, MELVILLE, NY 11747-4501 USA</PA>
   <SN>0003-6951</SN>
   <EI></EI>
   <BN></BN>
   <J9>APPL PHYS LETT</J9>
   <JI>Appl. Phys. Lett.</JI>
   <PD>JUL 2</PD>
   <PY>2012</PY>
   <VL>101</VL>
   <IS>1</IS>
   <PN></PN>
   <SU></SU>
   <SI></SI>
   <MA></MA>
   <BP></BP>
   <EP></EP>
   <AR>013110</AR>
   <DI>10.1063/1.4731640</DI>
   <D2></D2>
   <PG>4</PG>
   <WC>Physics, Applied</WC>
   <SC>Physics</SC>
   <GA>970PM</GA>
   <UT>WOS:000306144800065</UT>
   <PM></PM>
</bibliography>
