<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<bibliography>
   <PT>J</PT>
   <AU>Shi, Z; Qiu, XP; Zhu, JT; Chantrell, RW; Mangin, S; Zhou, SM</AU>
   <BA></BA>
   <BE></BE>
   <GP></GP>
   <AF>Shi, Z.; Qiu, X. P.; Zhu, J. T.; Chantrell, R. W.; Mangin, S.; Zhou, S. M.</AF>
   <BF></BF>
   <CA></CA>
   <TI>Composition-controlled exchange bias training effect in FeCr/IrMn bilayers</TI>
   <SO>EUROPEAN PHYSICAL JOURNAL B</SO>
   <SE></SE>
   <BS></BS>
   <LA>English</LA>
   <DT>Article</DT>
   <CT></CT>
   <CY></CY>
   <CL></CL>
   <SP></SP>
   <HO></HO>
   <DE></DE>
   <ID>DEPENDENCE; MAGNETIZATION; ANISOTROPY; SYSTEMS</ID>
   <AB>For FeCr/IrMn bilayers, the exchange bias training effect and the magnetization reversal mechanism are correlated to each other and depend on the composition of the ferromagnetic layer. For high Fe contents, the asymmetric magnetization reversal is observed. During the training effect, both exchange field and coercivity decrease monotonically, suggesting a type I training effect. For low Fe contents, the domain wall depinning takes place for the two hysteresis loop branches. Only exchange field diminution happens in the training effect. The coercivity almost does not change in the process, corresponding to a type II training effect. It is suggested that the motion of antiferromagnetic spins is modified by the magnetization reversal mechanism in the ferromagnetic layer.</AB>
   <C1>[Shi, Z.; Zhu, J. T.; Zhou, S. M.] Tongji Univ, Shanghai Key Lab Special Artificial Microstruct M, Shanghai 200092, Peoples R China; [Shi, Z.; Zhu, J. T.; Zhou, S. M.] Tongji Univ, Dept Phys, Shanghai 200092, Peoples R China; [Qiu, X. P.] Fudan Univ, Natl Key Lab, Surface Phys Lab, Shanghai 200433, Peoples R China; [Qiu, X. P.] Fudan Univ, Dept Phys, Shanghai 200433, Peoples R China; [Chantrell, R. W.] Univ York, Dept Phys, York YO10 5DD, N Yorkshire, England; [Mangin, S.] Nancy Univ, Inst Jean Lamour, F-54506 Vandoeuvre Les Nancy, France</C1>
   <RP>Shi, Z (reprint author), Tongji Univ, Shanghai Key Lab Special Artificial Microstruct M, Shanghai 200092, Peoples R China.</RP>
   <EM>shizhong@tongji.edu.cn</EM>
   <RI>Shi, Zhong/B-5736-2012</RI>
   <OI>Shi, Zhong/0000-0002-6793-0304</OI>
   <FU>National Science Foundation of China [10974032, 50871030]; National Basic Research Program of China [2009CB929201]</FU>
   <FX>This work was supported by the National Science Foundation of China under grant Nos. 10974032 and 50871030, the National Basic Research Program of China under grant No. 2009CB929201.</FX>
   <CR></CR>
   <NR>35</NR>
   <TC>1</TC>
   <Z9>1</Z9>
   <PU>SPRINGER</PU>
   <PI>NEW YORK</PI>
   <PA>233 SPRING ST, NEW YORK, NY 10013 USA</PA>
   <SN>1434-6028</SN>
   <EI></EI>
   <BN></BN>
   <J9>EUR PHYS J B</J9>
   <JI>Eur. Phys. J. B</JI>
   <PD>NOV</PD>
   <PY>2011</PY>
   <VL>84</VL>
   <IS>2</IS>
   <PN></PN>
   <SU></SU>
   <SI></SI>
   <MA></MA>
   <BP>173</BP>
   <EP>176</EP>
   <AR></AR>
   <DI>10.1140/epjb/e2011-20808-3</DI>
   <D2></D2>
   <PG>4</PG>
   <WC>Physics, Condensed Matter</WC>
   <SC>Physics</SC>
   <GA>855DE</GA>
   <UT>WOS:000297543100003</UT>
   <PM></PM>
</bibliography>
