<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<bibliography>
   <PT>J</PT>
   <AU>Sukhostavets, OV; Pigeau, B; Sangiao, S; de Loubens, G; Naletov, VV; Klein, O; Mitsuzuka, K; Andrieu, S; Montaigne, F; Guslienko, KY</AU>
   <BA></BA>
   <BE></BE>
   <GP></GP>
   <AF>Sukhostavets, O. V.; Pigeau, B.; Sangiao, S.; de Loubens, G.; Naletov, V. V.; Klein, O.; Mitsuzuka, K.; Andrieu, S.; Montaigne, F.; Guslienko, K. Y.</AF>
   <BF></BF>
   <CA></CA>
   <TI>Probing the Anharmonicity of the Potential Well for a Magnetic Vortex Core in a Nanodot</TI>
   <SO>PHYSICAL REVIEW LETTERS</SO>
   <SE></SE>
   <BS></BS>
   <LA>English</LA>
   <DT>Article</DT>
   <CT></CT>
   <CY></CY>
   <CL></CL>
   <SP></SP>
   <HO></HO>
   <DE></DE>
   <ID>SPIN-POLARIZED CURRENT; DYNAMICS</ID>
   <AB>The anharmonicity of the potential well confining a magnetic vortex core in a nanodot is measured dynamically with a magnetic resonance force microscope (MRFM). The stray field of the MRFM tip is used to displace the equilibrium core position away from the nanodot center. The anharmonicity is then inferred from the relative frequency shift induced on the eigenfrequency of the vortex core translational mode. An analytical framework is proposed to extract the anharmonic coefficient from this variational approach. Traces of these shifts are recorded while scanning the tip above an isolated nanodot, patterned out of a single crystal FeV film. We observe a + 10% increase of the eigenfrequency when the equilibrium position of the vortex core is displaced to about one-third of its radius. This calibrates the tunability of the gyrotropic mode by external magnetic fields.</AB>
   <C1>[Sukhostavets, O. V.; Guslienko, K. Y.] Univ Basque Country, Dept Fis Mat, San Sebastian 20018, Spain; [Pigeau, B.; Sangiao, S.; de Loubens, G.; Naletov, V. V.; Klein, O.] CEA Saclay, CNRS, URA 2464, Serv Phys Etat Condense, F-91191 Gif Sur Yvette, France; [Naletov, V. V.] Kazan Fed Univ, Inst Phys, Kazan 420008, Russia; [Mitsuzuka, K.; Andrieu, S.; Montaigne, F.] Univ Lorraine, CNRS, UMR 7198, Inst Jean Lamour, F-54506 Nancy, France; [Guslienko, K. Y.] Basque Fdn Sci, IKERBASQUE, Bilbao 48011, Spain</C1>
   <RP>Klein, O (reprint author), CEA Saclay, CNRS, URA 2464, Serv Phys Etat Condense, F-91191 Gif Sur Yvette, France.</RP>
   <EM>oklein@cea.fr</EM>
   <RI>SANGIAO, SORAYA/B-6436-2013</RI>
   <OI>SANGIAO, SORAYA/0000-0002-4123-487X</OI>
   <FU>EU grant MOSAIC [ICT-FP7-317950]; French ANR Grant MARVEL [ANR-2010-JCJC-0410-01]; Spanish MEC [PIB2010US-0015, FIS2010-20979- C02-0]; Marie Curie grant AtomicFMR [IEF-301656]; IKERBASQUE (Basque Foundation for Science); UPV/EHU</FU>
   <FX>This research was partly supported by the EU grant MOSAIC (ICT-FP7-317950), the French ANR Grant MARVEL (ANR-2010-JCJC-0410-01), and the Spanish MEC Grants No. PIB2010US-00153 and No. FIS2010-20979- C02-01. S.S., K.G., and O.S. acknowledge support from the Marie Curie grant AtomicFMR (IEF-301656), from the IKERBASQUE (Basque Foundation for Science), and from the UPV/EHU, respectively.</FX>
   <CR></CR>
   <NR>25</NR>
   <TC>2</TC>
   <Z9>2</Z9>
   <PU>AMER PHYSICAL SOC</PU>
   <PI>COLLEGE PK</PI>
   <PA>ONE PHYSICS ELLIPSE, COLLEGE PK, MD 20740-3844 USA</PA>
   <SN>0031-9007</SN>
   <EI>1079-7114</EI>
   <BN></BN>
   <J9>PHYS REV LETT</J9>
   <JI>Phys. Rev. Lett.</JI>
   <PD>DEC 10</PD>
   <PY>2013</PY>
   <VL>111</VL>
   <IS>24</IS>
   <PN></PN>
   <SU></SU>
   <SI></SI>
   <MA></MA>
   <BP></BP>
   <EP></EP>
   <AR>247601</AR>
   <DI>10.1103/PhysRevLett.111.247601</DI>
   <D2></D2>
   <PG>5</PG>
   <WC>Physics, Multidisciplinary</WC>
   <SC>Physics</SC>
   <GA>275TB</GA>
   <UT>WOS:000328699400011</UT>
   <PM>24483698</PM>
</bibliography>
