<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<bibliography>
   <PT>J</PT>
   <AU>Mangin, S; Gottwald, M; Lambert, CH; Steil, D; Uhlir, V; Pang, L; Hehn, M; Alebrand, S; Cinchetti, M; Malinowski, G; Fainman, Y; Aeschlimann, M; Fullerton, EE</AU>
   <BA></BA>
   <BE></BE>
   <GP></GP>
   <AF>Mangin, S.; Gottwald, M.; Lambert, C-H.; Steil, D.; Uhlir, V.; Pang, L.; Hehn, M.; Alebrand, S.; Cinchetti, M.; Malinowski, G.; Fainman, Y.; Aeschlimann, M.; Fullerton, E. E.</AF>
   <BF></BF>
   <CA></CA>
   <TI>Engineered materials for all-optical helicity-dependent magnetic switching</TI>
   <SO>NATURE MATERIALS</SO>
   <SE></SE>
   <BS></BS>
   <LA>English</LA>
   <DT>Article</DT>
   <CT></CT>
   <CY></CY>
   <CL></CL>
   <SP></SP>
   <HO></HO>
   <DE></DE>
   <ID>TRANSITION-METAL ALLOYS; MAGNETOOPTICAL PROPERTIES; REVERSAL; ANISOTROPY; MULTILAYERS; DRIVEN; FE; CO</ID>
   <AB>The possibility of manipulating magnetic systems without applied magnetic fields have attracted growing attention over the past fifteen years. The low-power manipulation of the magnetization, preferably at ultrashort timescales, has become a fundamental challenge with implications for future magnetic information memory and storage technologies. Here we explore the optical manipulation of the magnetization in engineered magnetic materials. We demonstrate that all-optical helicity-dependent switching (AO-HDS) can be observed not only in selected rare earth-transition metal (RE-TM) alloy films but also in a much broader variety of materials, including RE-TMalloys, multilayers and heterostructures. We further show that RE-free Co-Ir-based synthetic ferrimagnetic heterostructures designed to mimic the magnetic properties of RE-TM alloys also exhibit AO-HDS. These results challenge present theories of AO-HDS and provide a pathway to engineering materials for future applications based on all-optical control of magnetic order.</AB>
   <C1>[Mangin, S.; Gottwald, M.; Lambert, C-H.; Uhlir, V.; Fullerton, E. E.] Univ Calif San Diego, Ctr Magnet Recording Res, La Jolla, CA 92093 USA; [Mangin, S.; Lambert, C-H.; Hehn, M.; Malinowski, G.] Univ Lorraine, UMR CNRS 7198, Inst Jean Lamour, F-54506 Vandoeuvre Les Nancy, France; [Steil, D.; Alebrand, S.; Cinchetti, M.; Aeschlimann, M.] Univ Kaiserslautern, Dept Phys, D-67663 Kaiserslautern, Germany; [Steil, D.; Alebrand, S.; Cinchetti, M.; Aeschlimann, M.] Univ Kaiserslautern, Res Ctr OPTIMAS, D-67663 Kaiserslautern, Germany; [Pang, L.; Fainman, Y.; Fullerton, E. E.] Univ Calif San Diego, Dept Elect & Comp Engn, La Jolla, CA 92093 USA; [Malinowski, G.] Univ Paris 11, Lab Phys Solides, CNRS UMR 8502, F-91405 Orsay, France</C1>
   <RP>Mangin, S (reprint author), Univ Calif San Diego, Ctr Magnet Recording Res, La Jolla, CA 92093 USA.</RP>
   <EM>stephane.mangin@univ-lorraine.fr; efullerton@ucsd.edu</EM>
   <RI>Cinchetti, Mirko/F-9769-2010; Fullerton, Eric/H-8445-2013; Uhlir, Vojtech/E-6860-2011</RI>
   <OI>Cinchetti, Mirko/0000-0003-0735-8921; Fullerton, Eric/0000-0002-4725-9509; </OI>
   <FU>ANR [ANR-10-BLANC-1005]; Advanced Storage Technology Consortium; Office of Naval Research (ONR) MURI programme; Partner University Fund 'Novel Magnetic Materials for Spin Torque Physics'; European Project [OP2M FP7-IOF-2011-298060]; Region Lorraine; DOE, Office of Basic Energy Sciences [DE-SC0003678]</FU>
   <FX>We would like to thank M. Fuhrman and R. Tolley for technical assistance with optical measurements and fruitful discussion, and J. M. Dubois for his constant support. This work was supported by the ANR, ANR-10-BLANC-1005 'Friends', and work at UCSD was partially supported by a grant from the Advanced Storage Technology Consortium and the Office of Naval Research (ONR) MURI programme. It was also supported by The Partner University Fund 'Novel Magnetic Materials for Spin Torque Physics' as well as the European Project (OP2M FP7-IOF-2011-298060) and the Region Lorraine. V. U. was supported by DOE, Office of Basic Energy Sciences award #DE-SC0003678.</FX>
   <CR></CR>
   <NR>35</NR>
   <TC>15</TC>
   <Z9>15</Z9>
   <PU>NATURE PUBLISHING GROUP</PU>
   <PI>LONDON</PI>
   <PA>MACMILLAN BUILDING, 4 CRINAN ST, LONDON N1 9XW, ENGLAND</PA>
   <SN>1476-1122</SN>
   <EI>1476-4660</EI>
   <BN></BN>
   <J9>NAT MATER</J9>
   <JI>Nat. Mater.</JI>
   <PD>MAR</PD>
   <PY>2014</PY>
   <VL>13</VL>
   <IS>3</IS>
   <PN></PN>
   <SU></SU>
   <SI></SI>
   <MA></MA>
   <BP>287</BP>
   <EP>293</EP>
   <AR></AR>
   <DI>10.1038/NMAT3864</DI>
   <D2></D2>
   <PG>7</PG>
   <WC>Chemistry, Physical; Materials Science, Multidisciplinary; Physics, Applied; Physics, Condensed Matter</WC>
   <SC>Chemistry; Materials Science; Physics</SC>
   <GA>AB7BV</GA>
   <UT>WOS:000331945200024</UT>
   <PM>24531398</PM>
</bibliography>
