<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<bibliography>
   <PT>J</PT>
   <AU>Mitsuzuka, K; Lacour, D; Hehn, M; Andrieu, S; Montaigne, F</AU>
   <BA></BA>
   <BE></BE>
   <GP></GP>
   <AF>Mitsuzuka, K.; Lacour, D.; Hehn, M.; Andrieu, S.; Montaigne, F.</AF>
   <BF></BF>
   <CA></CA>
   <TI>Magnetic vortices in single crystalline Fe-V disks with four folds magnetic anisotropy</TI>
   <SO>APPLIED PHYSICS LETTERS</SO>
   <SE></SE>
   <BS></BS>
   <LA>English</LA>
   <DT>Article</DT>
   <CT></CT>
   <CY></CY>
   <CL></CL>
   <SP></SP>
   <HO></HO>
   <DE></DE>
   <ID></ID>
   <AB>Magnetic vortices in circular disks made from Fe-V single crystal film have been studied by magnetic force microscopy. At remanent state, all the disks host a single vortex structure. The magnetic contrast differs drastically from the one usually observed in "traditional" materials and reveals the influence of the four folds anisotropy originating from the bcc structure of Fe-V lattice. Field dependence of vortex position has been studied. The vortex displacement is observed to be perpendicular to the field and depends on the field direction. Micromagnetic simulations reproduce quantitatively this behavior and explain the influence of cubic magnetic anisotropy. (C) 2012 American Institute of Physics. [http://dx.doi.org/10.1063/1.4711219]</AB>
   <C1>[Mitsuzuka, K.; Lacour, D.; Hehn, M.; Andrieu, S.; Montaigne, F.] Univ Lorraine, CNRS, Inst Jean Lamour, F-54506 Vandoeuvre Les Nancy, France</C1>
   <RP>Mitsuzuka, K (reprint author), Univ Lorraine, CNRS, Inst Jean Lamour, Blvd Aiguillettes BP 70239, F-54506 Vandoeuvre Les Nancy, France.</RP>
   <EM></EM>
   <RI></RI>
   <OI></OI>
   <FU>ANR [ANR-09-NANO-006]</FU>
   <FX>This work has been partially supported by the ANR Grant VOICE (ANR-09-NANO-006). The authors acknowledge support from G. Lengaigne and S. Mc Murtry for the nanofabrication process, S. Robert for x-ray diffraction measurements, and T. Devolder and R. Otxoa for VNA-FMR measurements and fruitful discussions.</FX>
   <CR></CR>
   <NR>17</NR>
   <TC>3</TC>
   <Z9>3</Z9>
   <PU>AMER INST PHYSICS</PU>
   <PI>MELVILLE</PI>
   <PA>CIRCULATION & FULFILLMENT DIV, 2 HUNTINGTON QUADRANGLE, STE 1 N O 1, MELVILLE, NY 11747-4501 USA</PA>
   <SN>0003-6951</SN>
   <EI></EI>
   <BN></BN>
   <J9>APPL PHYS LETT</J9>
   <JI>Appl. Phys. Lett.</JI>
   <PD>MAY 7</PD>
   <PY>2012</PY>
   <VL>100</VL>
   <IS>19</IS>
   <PN></PN>
   <SU></SU>
   <SI></SI>
   <MA></MA>
   <BP></BP>
   <EP></EP>
   <AR>192406</AR>
   <DI>10.1063/1.4711219</DI>
   <D2></D2>
   <PG>4</PG>
   <WC>Physics, Applied</WC>
   <SC>Physics</SC>
   <GA>943GG</GA>
   <UT>WOS:000304108000051</UT>
   <PM></PM>
</bibliography>
