<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<bibliography>
   <PT>J</PT>
   <AU>Bedau, D; Liu, H; Bouzaglou, JJ; Kent, AD; Sun, JZ; Katine, JA; Fullerton, EE; Mangin, S</AU>
   <BA></BA>
   <BE></BE>
   <GP></GP>
   <AF>Bedau, D.; Liu, H.; Bouzaglou, J. -J.; Kent, A. D.; Sun, J. Z.; Katine, J. A.; Fullerton, E. E.; Mangin, S.</AF>
   <BF></BF>
   <CA></CA>
   <TI>Ultrafast spin-transfer switching in spin valve nanopillars with perpendicular anisotropy</TI>
   <SO>APPLIED PHYSICS LETTERS</SO>
   <SE></SE>
   <BS></BS>
   <LA>English</LA>
   <DT>Article</DT>
   <CT></CT>
   <CY></CY>
   <CL></CL>
   <SP></SP>
   <HO></HO>
   <DE>perpendicular magnetic anisotropy; spin valves</DE>
   <ID>ANGULAR-MOMENTUM TRANSFER; MAGNETIZATION REVERSAL</ID>
   <AB>Spin-transfer switching with short current pulses has been studied in spin-valve nanopillars with perpendicularly magnetized free and reference layers. Magnetization switching with current pulses as short as 300 ps is demonstrated. The pulse amplitude needed to reverse the magnetization is shown to be inversely proportional to the pulse duration, consistent with a macrospin spin-transfer model. However, the pulse amplitude duration switching boundary depends on the applied field much more strongly than predicted by the zero temperature macrospin model. The results also demonstrate that there is an optimal pulse length that minimizes the energy required to reverse the magnetization.</AB>
   <C1>[Bedau, D.; Liu, H.; Bouzaglou, J. -J.; Kent, A. D.] NYU, Dept Phys, New York, NY 10003 USA; [Sun, J. Z.] IBM TJ Watson Res Ctr, Yorktown Hts, NY 10598 USA; [Katine, J. A.] Hitachi GST, San Jose Res Ctr, San Jose, CA 95135 USA; [Fullerton, E. E.] Univ Calif San Diego, CMRR, La Jolla, CA 92093 USA; [Bouzaglou, J. -J.; Mangin, S.] Nancy Univ, IJL, CNRS, UMR 7198, F-54042 Nancy, France</C1>
   <RP>Bedau, D (reprint author), NYU, Dept Phys, 4 Washington Pl, New York, NY 10003 USA.</RP>
   <EM>db137@nyu.edu</EM>
   <RI>Fullerton, Eric/H-8445-2013; Sun, Jonathan/C-2773-2009</RI>
   <OI>Fullerton, Eric/0000-0002-4725-9509; </OI>
   <FU>USARO [W911NF0710643]</FU>
   <FX>The research at NYU was supported by USARO (Grant No. W911NF0710643).</FX>
   <CR></CR>
   <NR>17</NR>
   <TC>46</TC>
   <Z9>46</Z9>
   <PU>AMER INST PHYSICS</PU>
   <PI>MELVILLE</PI>
   <PA>CIRCULATION & FULFILLMENT DIV, 2 HUNTINGTON QUADRANGLE, STE 1 N O 1, MELVILLE, NY 11747-4501 USA</PA>
   <SN>0003-6951</SN>
   <EI></EI>
   <BN></BN>
   <J9>APPL PHYS LETT</J9>
   <JI>Appl. Phys. Lett.</JI>
   <PD>JAN 11</PD>
   <PY>2010</PY>
   <VL>96</VL>
   <IS>2</IS>
   <PN></PN>
   <SU></SU>
   <SI></SI>
   <MA></MA>
   <BP></BP>
   <EP></EP>
   <AR>022514</AR>
   <DI>10.1063/1.3284515</DI>
   <D2></D2>
   <PG>3</PG>
   <WC>Physics, Applied</WC>
   <SC>Physics</SC>
   <GA>544WD</GA>
   <UT>WOS:000273689400040</UT>
   <PM></PM>
</bibliography>
