<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<bibliography>
   <PT>J</PT>
   <AU>Girod, S; Bubendorff, JL; Montaigne, F; Simon, L; Lacour, D; Hehn, M</AU>
   <BA></BA>
   <BE></BE>
   <GP></GP>
   <AF>Girod, S.; Bubendorff, J-L; Montaigne, F.; Simon, L.; Lacour, D.; Hehn, M.</AF>
   <BF></BF>
   <CA></CA>
   <TI>Real time atomic force microscopy imaging during nanogap formation by electromigration</TI>
   <SO>NANOTECHNOLOGY</SO>
   <SE></SE>
   <BS></BS>
   <LA>English</LA>
   <DT>Article</DT>
   <CT></CT>
   <CY></CY>
   <CL></CL>
   <SP></SP>
   <HO></HO>
   <DE></DE>
   <ID>FABRICATION; TRANSISTOR; ELECTRODES</ID>
   <AB>We present real time atomic force microscopy imaging during nanogap fabrication by feedback controlled electromigration of a gold nanowire. The correlated measurements of electrical resistance and atomic force microscopy reveal that the major structural changes appear at the early stage of the process. Moreover, despite important morphological changes, the resistance of the nanowire shows a weak increase of just a few ohms. The detailed analysis of the atomic force microscopy images clearly shows that the electromigration process is strongly influenced by the initial microstructure of the nanowire.</AB>
   <C1>[Girod, S.; Montaigne, F.; Lacour, D.; Hehn, M.] Univ Lorraine, CNRS, Inst Jean Lamour, F-54506 Vandoeuvre Les Nancy, France; [Bubendorff, J-L; Simon, L.] Univ Haute Alsace, IS2M LRC CNRS 7228, Inst Sci Mat Mulhouse, F-68093 Mulhouse, France</C1>
   <RP>Girod, S (reprint author), Univ Lorraine, CNRS, Inst Jean Lamour, Blvd Aiguillettes,BP 70239, F-54506 Vandoeuvre Les Nancy, France.</RP>
   <EM>francois.montaigne@ijl.nancy-universite.fr</EM>
   <RI></RI>
   <OI></OI>
   <FU>ANR grant TRANSFILSEN [ANR-09-BLA-196]</FU>
   <FX>This work has been partially supported by the ANR grant TRANSFILSEN (ANR-09-BLA-196). The authors acknowledge support from G Lengaigne and S Mc Murtry for the nanofabrication process, S Robert and O Lenoble for x-ray diffraction measurements, E Denys and A Florentin for the AFM setup.</FX>
   <CR></CR>
   <NR>18</NR>
   <TC>3</TC>
   <Z9>3</Z9>
   <PU>IOP PUBLISHING LTD</PU>
   <PI>BRISTOL</PI>
   <PA>TEMPLE CIRCUS, TEMPLE WAY, BRISTOL BS1 6BE, ENGLAND</PA>
   <SN>0957-4484</SN>
   <EI></EI>
   <BN></BN>
   <J9>NANOTECHNOLOGY</J9>
   <JI>Nanotechnology</JI>
   <PD>SEP 14</PD>
   <PY>2012</PY>
   <VL>23</VL>
   <IS>36</IS>
   <PN></PN>
   <SU></SU>
   <SI></SI>
   <MA></MA>
   <BP></BP>
   <EP></EP>
   <AR>365302</AR>
   <DI>10.1088/0957-4484/23/36/365302</DI>
   <D2></D2>
   <PG>4</PG>
   <WC>Nanoscience & Nanotechnology; Materials Science, Multidisciplinary; Physics, Applied</WC>
   <SC>Science & Technology - Other Topics; Materials Science; Physics</SC>
   <GA>992XD</GA>
   <UT>WOS:000307812800008</UT>
   <PM>22914506</PM>
</bibliography>
