<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<bibliography>
   <PT>J</PT>
   <AU>Lambert, CH; Mangin, S; Varaprasad, BSDCS; Takahashi, YK; Hehn, M; Cinchetti, M; Malinowski, G; Hono, K; Fainman, Y; Aeschlimann, M; Fullerton, EE</AU>
   <BA></BA>
   <BE></BE>
   <GP></GP>
   <AF>Lambert, C-H; Mangin, S.; Varaprasad, B. S. D. Ch S.; Takahashi, Y. K.; Hehn, M.; Cinchetti, M.; Malinowski, G.; Hono, K.; Fainman, Y.; Aeschlimann, M.; Fullerton, E. E.</AF>
   <BF></BF>
   <CA></CA>
   <TI>All-optical control of ferromagnetic thin films and nanostructures</TI>
   <SO>SCIENCE</SO>
   <SE></SE>
   <BS></BS>
   <LA>English</LA>
   <DT>Article</DT>
   <CT></CT>
   <CY></CY>
   <CL></CL>
   <SP></SP>
   <HO></HO>
   <DE></DE>
   <ID>MAGNETIZATION REVERSAL; ANGULAR-MOMENTUM; ULTRAFAST; DEMAGNETIZATION</ID>
   <AB>The interplay of light and magnetism allowed light to be used as a probe of magnetic materials. Now the focus has shifted to use polarized light to alter or manipulate magnetism. Here, we demonstrate optical control of ferromagnetic materials ranging from magnetic thin films to multilayers and even granular films being explored for ultra-high-density magnetic recording. Our finding shows that optical control of magnetic materials is a much more general phenomenon than previously assumed and may have a major impact on data memory and storage industries through the integration of optical control of ferromagnetic bits.</AB>
   <C1>[Lambert, C-H; Mangin, S.; Fullerton, E. E.] Univ Calif San Diego, Ctr Magnet Recording Res, La Jolla, CA 92093 USA; [Lambert, C-H; Mangin, S.; Hehn, M.; Malinowski, G.] Univ Lorraine, CNRS, UMR 7198, Inst Jean Lamour, F-54506 Vandoeuvre Les Nancy, France; [Varaprasad, B. S. D. Ch S.; Takahashi, Y. K.; Hono, K.] Natl Inst Mat Sci, Magnet Mat Unit, Tsukuba, Ibaraki 3050047, Japan; [Cinchetti, M.; Aeschlimann, M.] Univ Kaiserslautern, Dept Phys, D-67663 Kaiserslautern, Germany; [Cinchetti, M.; Aeschlimann, M.] Univ Kaiserslautern, Res Ctr OPTIMAS, D-67663 Kaiserslautern, Germany; [Fainman, Y.; Fullerton, E. E.] Univ Calif San Diego, Dept Elect & Comp Engn, La Jolla, CA 92093 USA</C1>
   <RP>Mangin, S (reprint author), Univ Calif San Diego, Ctr Magnet Recording Res, La Jolla, CA 92093 USA.</RP>
   <EM>stephane.mangin@univ-lorraine.fr; efullerton@ucsd.edu</EM>
   <RI>Fullerton, Eric/H-8445-2013; Cinchetti, Mirko/F-9769-2010</RI>
   <OI>Fullerton, Eric/0000-0002-4725-9509; Cinchetti, Mirko/0000-0003-0735-8921</OI>
   <FU>Agence Nationale de la Recherche (ANR) [ANR-10-BLANC-1005]; Office of Naval Research (ONR) Multidisciplinary University Initiative (MURI) program; Advanced Storage Technology Consortium; Partner University Fund " Novel Magnetic Materials for Spin Torque Physics"; European Project [OP2M FP7-IOF-2011-298060]; Region Lorraine</FU>
   <FX>We thank R. Tolley and M. Gottwald for help on sample fabrication and M. Menarini and V. Lomakin for helpful discussions. This work was supported by the Agence Nationale de la Recherche (ANR), ANR-10-BLANC-1005 "Friends," and work at University of California San Diego was supported by the Office of Naval Research (ONR) Multidisciplinary University Initiative (MURI) program and a grant from the Advanced Storage Technology Consortium. It was also supported by the Partner University Fund " Novel Magnetic Materials for Spin Torque Physics" as well as the European Project (OP2M FP7-IOF-2011-298060) and the Region Lorraine. Work at the National Institute for Materials Science was supported by Advanced Storage Technology Consortium. Author contributions include the following: S.M., M.A., M.C., Y.S., and E.E.F. designed and coordinated the project; C.-H. L. grew, characterized, and optimized the thin films samples, while B.S.D.Ch.S.V., Y.K.T., and K.H. developed and grew the FePt-based granular media. C.-H.L., S.M., and Y.K.T. operated the Kerr microscope and the pump laser experiment. S. M. and E. E. F. coordinated work on the paper with contributions from C.-H.L, M.H., M.C., and G.M., with regular discussions with all authors.</FX>
   <CR></CR>
   <NR>30</NR>
   <TC>2</TC>
   <Z9>2</Z9>
   <PU>AMER ASSOC ADVANCEMENT SCIENCE</PU>
   <PI>WASHINGTON</PI>
   <PA>1200 NEW YORK AVE, NW, WASHINGTON, DC 20005 USA</PA>
   <SN>0036-8075</SN>
   <EI>1095-9203</EI>
   <BN></BN>
   <J9>SCIENCE</J9>
   <JI>Science</JI>
   <PD>SEP 12</PD>
   <PY>2014</PY>
   <VL>345</VL>
   <IS>6202</IS>
   <PN></PN>
   <SU></SU>
   <SI></SI>
   <MA></MA>
   <BP>1337</BP>
   <EP>1340</EP>
   <AR></AR>
   <DI>10.1126/science.1253493</DI>
   <D2></D2>
   <PG>4</PG>
   <WC>Multidisciplinary Sciences</WC>
   <SC>Science & Technology - Other Topics</SC>
   <GA>AO6TG</GA>
   <UT>WOS:000341483800062</UT>
   <PM>25147280</PM>
</bibliography>
