<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<bibliography>
   <PT>J</PT>
   <AU>Briones, E; Briones, J; Cuadrado, A; Martinez-Anton, JC; McMurtry, S; Hehn, M; Montaigne, F; Alda, J; Gonzalez, FJ</AU>
   <BA></BA>
   <BE></BE>
   <GP></GP>
   <AF>Briones, E.; Briones, J.; Cuadrado, A.; Martinez-Anton, J. C.; McMurtry, S.; Hehn, M.; Montaigne, F.; Alda, J.; Gonzalez, F. J.</AF>
   <BF></BF>
   <CA></CA>
   <TI>Seebeck nanoantennas for solar energy harvesting</TI>
   <SO>APPLIED PHYSICS LETTERS</SO>
   <SE></SE>
   <BS></BS>
   <LA>English</LA>
   <DT>Article</DT>
   <CT></CT>
   <CY></CY>
   <CL></CL>
   <SP></SP>
   <HO></HO>
   <DE></DE>
   <ID>INFRARED DETECTION; THERMOELECTRIC MICROGENERATORS; NANO-RECTENNA; ANTENNAS; EFFICIENCY; DETECTORS; DIPOLE; OPTIMIZATION; GENERATION; HEAT</ID>
   <AB>We propose a mid-infrared device based on thermocouple optical antennas for light sensing and energy harvesting applications. We numerically demonstrate that antennas are able to generate low-power dc signals by beneficing of the thermoelectric properties of the metals that constitute them. We theoretically evaluate the optical-to-electrical conversion efficiency for harvesting applications and finally discuss strategies to increase its performance. Thermocouple optical antennas therefore open the route toward the design of photovoltaic devices. (C) 2014 AIP Publishing LLC.</AB>
   <C1>[Briones, E.; Gonzalez, F. J.] Univ Autonoma San Luis Potosi, CIACyT, San Luis Potosi 78210, Mexico; [Briones, J.] Jesuit Univ Guadalajara, ITESO, Dept Math & Phys, Tlaquepaque 45604, Jalisco, Mexico; [Cuadrado, A.; Martinez-Anton, J. C.; Alda, J.] Univ Complutense Madrid, Fac Opt & Optometry, Madrid 28037, Spain; [McMurtry, S.; Hehn, M.; Montaigne, F.] Univ Lorraine, CNRS, Inst Jean Lamour, F-54506 Vandoeuvre Les Nancy, France</C1>
   <RP>Briones, E (reprint author), Univ Autonoma San Luis Potosi, CIACyT, San Luis Potosi 78210, Mexico.</RP>
   <EM>edgar.briones@uaslp.mx</EM>
   <RI></RI>
   <OI></OI>
   <FU>CONACYT-Mexico [CV-40859]; FONDECYT-Chile [3120059]; Spanish Ministerio de Innovacion [ENE2009-013430]; Project "Centro Mexicano de Innovacion en Energia Solar" from "Fondo Sectorial CONACYT-Secretaria de Energia-Sustentabilidad Energetica"; La Region Lorraine (France)</FU>
   <FX>Support from CONACYT-Mexico under postdoctoral grant CV-40859, FONDECYT-Chile under Project 3120059, Project ENE2009-013430 from the Spanish Ministerio de Innovacion, Project "Centro Mexicano de Innovacion en Energia Solar" from "Fondo Sectorial CONACYT-Secretaria de Energia-Sustentabilidad Energetica," and La Region Lorraine (France), is gratefully acknowledged.</FX>
   <CR></CR>
   <NR>40</NR>
   <TC>0</TC>
   <Z9>0</Z9>
   <PU>AMER INST PHYSICS</PU>
   <PI>MELVILLE</PI>
   <PA>CIRCULATION & FULFILLMENT DIV, 2 HUNTINGTON QUADRANGLE, STE 1 N O 1, MELVILLE, NY 11747-4501 USA</PA>
   <SN>0003-6951</SN>
   <EI>1077-3118</EI>
   <BN></BN>
   <J9>APPL PHYS LETT</J9>
   <JI>Appl. Phys. Lett.</JI>
   <PD>SEP 1</PD>
   <PY>2014</PY>
   <VL>105</VL>
   <IS>9</IS>
   <PN></PN>
   <SU></SU>
   <SI></SI>
   <MA></MA>
   <BP></BP>
   <EP></EP>
   <AR>093108</AR>
   <DI>10.1063/1.4895028</DI>
   <D2></D2>
   <PG>4</PG>
   <WC>Physics, Applied</WC>
   <SC>Physics</SC>
   <GA>AQ4FX</GA>
   <UT>WOS:000342749800052</UT>
   <PM></PM>
</bibliography>
