<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<bibliography>
   <PT>J</PT>
   <AU>Lambert, CH; Rajanikanth, A; Hauet, T; Mangin, S; Fullerton, EE; Andrieu, S</AU>
   <BA></BA>
   <BE></BE>
   <GP></GP>
   <AF>Lambert, C-H.; Rajanikanth, A.; Hauet, T.; Mangin, S.; Fullerton, E. E.; Andrieu, S.</AF>
   <BF></BF>
   <CA></CA>
   <TI>Quantifying perpendicular magnetic anisotropy at the Fe-MgO(001) interface</TI>
   <SO>APPLIED PHYSICS LETTERS</SO>
   <SE></SE>
   <BS></BS>
   <LA>English</LA>
   <DT>Article</DT>
   <CT></CT>
   <CY></CY>
   <CL></CL>
   <SP></SP>
   <HO></HO>
   <DE></DE>
   <ID>ATOMIC LAYERS; SUPERLATTICES; IRON</ID>
   <AB>We show that Fe-MgO interfaces possess strong perpendicular magnetic anisotropy of 1.0 +/- 0.1 erg/cm(2) in fully epitaxial MgO/V/Fe/MgO(001) and MgO/Cr/Fe/MgO(001) heterostructures. The sign and amplitude of the total anisotropy are quantified as a function of Fe thickness using magnetometry and ferromagnetic resonance. There is a transition from out-of-plane to in-plane anisotropy for 6 Fe monolayers in V/Fe/MgO and only 4 monolayers in Cr/Fe/MgO. A detailed study of the Fe magnetization and effective anisotropy in both systems explains this difference and quantifies the Fe-MgO interface anisotropy. (C) 2013 American Institute of Physics. [http://dx.doi.org/10.1063/1.4798291]</AB>
   <C1>[Lambert, C-H.; Rajanikanth, A.; Hauet, T.; Mangin, S.; Andrieu, S.] Univ Lorraine, CNRS, UMR 7198, Inst Jean Lamour, F-54506 Vandoeuvre Les Nancy, France; [Lambert, C-H.; Fullerton, E. E.] Univ Calif San Diego, Ctr Magnet Recording Res, San Diego, CA 92093 USA</C1>
   <RP>Andrieu, S (reprint author), Univ Lorraine, CNRS, UMR 7198, Inst Jean Lamour, F-54506 Vandoeuvre Les Nancy, France.</RP>
   <EM>stephane.andrieu@ijl.nancy-universite.fr</EM>
   <RI>Fullerton, Eric/H-8445-2013</RI>
   <OI>Fullerton, Eric/0000-0002-4725-9509</OI>
   <FU>French Agence Nationale de la Recherche [ANR-10-BLANC-1005 "Friends,", ANR-2010-BLANC-1006 "Elecmade"]; NSF [1002147]; Partner University Fund "Novel Magnetic Materials for Spin Torque Physics"; European Project [OP2M FP7-IOF-2011-298060]; Region Lorraine</FU>
   <FX>This work was supported by the French Agence Nationale de la Recherche, ANR-10-BLANC-1005 "Friends," ANR-2010-BLANC-1006 "Elecmade," and work at UCSD was supported by NSF Award # 1002147. It was also supported by The Partner University Fund "Novel Magnetic Materials for Spin Torque Physics" as well as the European Project (OP2M FP7-IOF-2011-298060) and the Region Lorraine.</FX>
   <CR></CR>
   <NR>35</NR>
   <TC>15</TC>
   <Z9>15</Z9>
   <PU>AMER INST PHYSICS</PU>
   <PI>MELVILLE</PI>
   <PA>CIRCULATION & FULFILLMENT DIV, 2 HUNTINGTON QUADRANGLE, STE 1 N O 1, MELVILLE, NY 11747-4501 USA</PA>
   <SN>0003-6951</SN>
   <EI></EI>
   <BN></BN>
   <J9>APPL PHYS LETT</J9>
   <JI>Appl. Phys. Lett.</JI>
   <PD>MAR 25</PD>
   <PY>2013</PY>
   <VL>102</VL>
   <IS>12</IS>
   <PN></PN>
   <SU></SU>
   <SI></SI>
   <MA></MA>
   <BP></BP>
   <EP></EP>
   <AR>122410</AR>
   <DI>10.1063/1.4798291</DI>
   <D2></D2>
   <PG>4</PG>
   <WC>Physics, Applied</WC>
   <SC>Physics</SC>
   <GA>117QB</GA>
   <UT>WOS:000316967100058</UT>
   <PM></PM>
</bibliography>
