<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<bibliography>
   <PT>J</PT>
   <AU>Bernos, J; Hehn, M; Montaigne, F; Tiusan, C; Lacour, D; Alnot, M; Negulescu, B; Lengaigne, G; Snoeck, E; Aliev, FG</AU>
   <BA></BA>
   <BE></BE>
   <GP></GP>
   <AF>Bernos, J.; Hehn, M.; Montaigne, F.; Tiusan, C.; Lacour, D.; Alnot, M.; Negulescu, B.; Lengaigne, G.; Snoeck, E.; Aliev, F. G.</AF>
   <BF></BF>
   <CA></CA>
   <TI>Impact of electron-electron interactions induced by disorder at interfaces on spin-dependent tunneling in Co-Fe-B/MgO/Co-Fe-B magnetic tunnel junctions</TI>
   <SO>PHYSICAL REVIEW B</SO>
   <SE></SE>
   <BS></BS>
   <LA>English</LA>
   <DT>Article</DT>
   <CT></CT>
   <CY></CY>
   <CL></CL>
   <SP></SP>
   <HO></HO>
   <DE></DE>
   <ID>METAL-INSULATOR-TRANSITION; ROOM-TEMPERATURE; MAGNETORESISTANCE; RESISTANCE; BARRIERS; SPECTRA</ID>
   <AB>In this study, we demonstrate that, beyond the standard magnon excitations, the electron-electron interactions in presence of disorder in CoFeB electrodes play a significant role on the zero-bias anomaly measured in CoFeB/MgO/CoFeB junctions. The low-temperature dependence of the tunneling conductance presents cusp-like dip at low voltage varying as the square root of the bias voltage. The amplitude of this zero-bias anomaly decreases with the annealing temperature, indicating interface crystallization and related increase in the tunnel magnetoresistance.</AB>
   <C1>[Bernos, J.; Hehn, M.; Montaigne, F.; Tiusan, C.; Lacour, D.; Alnot, M.; Negulescu, B.; Lengaigne, G.] Nancy Univ, Inst Jean Lamour, CNRS, UMR 7198, F-54506 Vandoeuvre Les Nancy, France; [Snoeck, E.] CEMES, F-31055 Toulouse, France; [Aliev, F. G.] Univ Autonoma Madrid, Dept Fis Mat Condensada, Canto Blanco 28049, Spain</C1>
   <RP>Bernos, J (reprint author), Nancy Univ, Inst Jean Lamour, CNRS, UMR 7198, Bd Aiguillettes,BP 239, F-54506 Vandoeuvre Les Nancy, France.</RP>
   <EM></EM>
   <RI>Tiusan, Coriolan/F-1564-2011</RI>
   <OI>Tiusan, Coriolan/0000-0003-1338-3867</OI>
   <FU>ANR [FR2009-0010]; CNRS; Spanish MICINN [MAT2009-10139, CSD2007-00010), CAM (P2009/MAT-1726)]</FU>
   <FX>The authors would like to thank D. Malterre, Ph. Mangin, and F. Gautier for fruitful discussions, S. Suire for technical assistance, and S. Girod for help with some measurements. This work was partially supported by ANR contracts CTS Lor-Al, Spinchat, SpinPress, and Spanish-French bilateral under Project No. FR2009-0010. One of the authors (E.S.) acknowledges financial support from the CNRS and CEA METSA network. F. G. A. acknowledges support by Spanish MICINN (MAT2009-10139, CSD2007-00010) and CAM (P2009/MAT-1726).</FX>
   <CR></CR>
   <NR>33</NR>
   <TC>9</TC>
   <Z9>9</Z9>
   <PU>AMER PHYSICAL SOC</PU>
   <PI>COLLEGE PK</PI>
   <PA>ONE PHYSICS ELLIPSE, COLLEGE PK, MD 20740-3844 USA</PA>
   <SN>1098-0121</SN>
   <EI></EI>
   <BN></BN>
   <J9>PHYS REV B</J9>
   <JI>Phys. Rev. B</JI>
   <PD>AUG 23</PD>
   <PY>2010</PY>
   <VL>82</VL>
   <IS>6</IS>
   <PN></PN>
   <SU></SU>
   <SI></SI>
   <MA></MA>
   <BP></BP>
   <EP></EP>
   <AR>060405</AR>
   <DI>10.1103/PhysRevB.82.060405</DI>
   <D2></D2>
   <PG>4</PG>
   <WC>Physics, Condensed Matter</WC>
   <SC>Physics</SC>
   <GA>641OX</GA>
   <UT>WOS:000281138900001</UT>
   <PM></PM>
</bibliography>
