<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<bibliography>
   <PT>J</PT>
   <AU>Gopman, DB; Bedau, D; Mangin, S; Fullerton, EE; Katine, JA; Kent, AD</AU>
   <BA></BA>
   <BE></BE>
   <GP></GP>
   <AF>Gopman, D. B.; Bedau, D.; Mangin, S.; Fullerton, E. E.; Katine, J. A.; Kent, A. D.</AF>
   <BF></BF>
   <CA></CA>
   <TI>Temperature dependent nucleation, propagation, and annihilation of domain walls in all-perpendicular spin-valve nanopillars</TI>
   <SO>JOURNAL OF APPLIED PHYSICS</SO>
   <SE></SE>
   <BS></BS>
   <LA>English</LA>
   <DT>Article</DT>
   <CT></CT>
   <CY></CY>
   <CL></CL>
   <SP></SP>
   <HO></HO>
   <DE>cobalt; magnetic domain walls; magnetic switching; magnetisation reversal; nanomagnetics; nanostructured materials; nickel; nucleation; spin valves</DE>
   <ID>WAVE RESONANCE; ANISOTROPY; FLUCTUATIONS; JUNCTION; FIELD</ID>
   <AB>We present a study of the temperature dependence of the switching fields in Co/Ni-based perpendicularly magnetized spin-valves. While magnetization reversal of all-perpendicular Co/Ni spin valves at ambient temperatures is typically marked by a single sharp step change in resistance, low temperature measurements can reveal a series of resistance steps, consistent with non-uniform magnetization configurations. We propose a model that consists of domain nucleation, propagation, and annihilation to explain the temperature dependence of the switching fields. Interestingly, low temperature (inf 30 K) step changes in resistance that we associate with domain nucleation have a bimodal switching field and resistance step distribution, attributable to two competing nucleation pathways.</AB>
   <C1>[Gopman, D. B.; Bedau, D.; Kent, A. D.] NYU, Dept Phys, New York, NY 10003 USA; [Bedau, D.; Katine, J. A.] HGST San Jose Res Ctr, San Jose, CA 95135 USA; [Mangin, S.] Univ Lorraine, CNRS, UMR 7198, Inst Jean Lamour, F-54506 Nancy, France; [Fullerton, E. E.] Univ Calif San Diego, CMRR, La Jolla, CA 92093 USA</C1>
   <RP>Gopman, DB (reprint author), NYU, Dept Phys, 4 Washington Pl, New York, NY 10003 USA.</RP>
   <EM>daniel.gopman@physics.nyu.edu</EM>
   <RI>Fullerton, Eric/H-8445-2013</RI>
   <OI>Fullerton, Eric/0000-0002-4725-9509</OI>
   <FU>NSF at NYU [DMR-1006575, NSF-DMR-1309202]; Partner University Fund (PUF) of the Embassy of France; Region Lorraine; NSF [DMR-1008654];  [ANR-10-BLANC-1005];  [OP2M FP7-IOF-2011-298060]</FU>
   <FX>This research was supported at NYU by NSF Grant Nos. DMR-1006575 and NSF-DMR-1309202, as well as the Partner University Fund (PUF) of the Embassy of France. Research at UL supported by ANR-10-BLANC-1005 "Friends," the European Project (OP2M FP7-IOF-2011-298060) and the Region Lorraine. Work at UCSD supported by NSF Grant No. DMR-1008654.</FX>
   <CR></CR>
   <NR>26</NR>
   <TC>0</TC>
   <Z9>0</Z9>
   <PU>AMER INST PHYSICS</PU>
   <PI>MELVILLE</PI>
   <PA>CIRCULATION & FULFILLMENT DIV, 2 HUNTINGTON QUADRANGLE, STE 1 N O 1, MELVILLE, NY 11747-4501 USA</PA>
   <SN>0021-8979</SN>
   <EI>1089-7550</EI>
   <BN></BN>
   <J9>J APPL PHYS</J9>
   <JI>J. Appl. Phys.</JI>
   <PD>MAR 21</PD>
   <PY>2014</PY>
   <VL>115</VL>
   <IS>11</IS>
   <PN></PN>
   <SU></SU>
   <SI></SI>
   <MA></MA>
   <BP></BP>
   <EP></EP>
   <AR>113910</AR>
   <DI>10.1063/1.4868159</DI>
   <D2></D2>
   <PG>12</PG>
   <WC>Physics, Applied</WC>
   <SC>Physics</SC>
   <GA>AE3TM</GA>
   <UT>WOS:000333900600036</UT>
   <PM></PM>
</bibliography>
